- Any sign of the police?
- No, no sign.
- 有没有看见警察？
- 没有，没看见。
- Looks like we're getting away with it.
- Good.
- 我们好像摆脱了。
- 好。
- How far is it to your father's boat?
- Two hours with luck.
- 还有多远才到你爸的船？
- 好运的话两小时。
Your luck seems to be very good,
touching wood.
你的运气好像挺好，百无禁忌。
Could you tell me now what happened?
I'd really like to know.
你现在可以告诉我什么事吗？我真的很想知道。
Only if you feel like it.
我希望你喜欢。
It's Charlotte Inwood.
是Charlotte Inwood。
- She's in a jam.
- That doesn't surprise me.
- 她有麻烦。
- 我不会感到惊讶。
No, this is serious, Eve.
Deadly serious.
不，是真的，Eve。
非常严重。
She was all over the place.
I had to help her. Anybody would have.
她会非常出名。我一定要帮她。每个人都会。
I was in my kitchen. It was about 5:00.
我在厨房。是五点钟。
The doorbell rang, and I went downstairs
to see who it was.
门铃响了，我下楼去看是谁。
Jonnie, you love me. Say that you
love me. You do love me, don't you?
Jonnie，你爱我。说你爱我。你真的爱我，是吗？
I think he's dead. I'm sure he's dead.
我想他死了。我肯定他死了。
I didn't mean it. I didn't mean it.
我不是故意的。我不是故意的。
- Who's dead?
- My husband.
- 谁自了？
- 我丈夫。
We had a terrible quarrel about you.
我们为你吵得很厉害。
Oh, he was vile.
You know the sort of things he can say.
噢，他非常粗鲁。
你也知道他什么都说得出口。
He started to hit me.
I grabbed something.
他开始打我。我拿起东西。
I was out of my mind with fear.
Oh, what am I to do?
我害怕得失去理智了。噢，我应该怎么办？
Darling, pull yourself together.
He may not be.
打令，控制一下你自己。他可能还没死。
The curtains, Jonnie. Draw the curtains.
窗帘，Jonnie。拉下窗帘。
I thought I had some brandy.
我想我还有些白兰地。
Here, drink this.
来，喝下。
He was an abominable man.
他是个坏蛋。
Why do women marry abominable men?
为什么女人要嫁给坏蛋？
- Where was all this?
- In my bedroom.
- 在哪里发生的？
- 在我的睡房。
- Anyone else in the house?
- I left the servants in the country.
- 有其他人在屋里吗？
- 我把佣人留在郊外。
I drove up early to have an hour's rest
before the performance.
我早点开车来想在表演前休息一小时。
Oh, what shall I do?
I can't go on. I can't.
噢，我应该怎么办？我不能继续下去。不能。
- Has anyone seen you?
- No. I don't think so.
- 有没有人看见你？
- 没有。应该没有。
There wasn't a soul in the street.
I jumped into my car and came here.
街上连人影都没有。我跳上车就来这里。
It's parked around the corner.
车就停在转角附近。
Oh, Jonnie, what will they do to me?
噢，Jonnie，他们会把我怎样？
Don't tremble like that. We'll find a way.
We'll see you're all right.
不要发抖。我们会想到办法的。你会没事的。
But you must call the theater.
I can't play tonight.
但你要通知剧院。我今晚不能表演。
Tell them I'm ill.
Heavens, it'll be true enough.
告诉他们我病了。天呀，这本来就是事实。
No, you must go on tonight.
You've got to.
不，你今晚一定要去。你必需去。
As if nothing had happened.
Nothing has happened.
就好像没事发生。没事发生。
You drove straight to the theater,
do you understand?
你马上开车去剧院，明白吗？
You haven't been home at all.
Now, get that into your head.
你根本没有回过家。现在，把这一点记住。
But my dress. There's blood on it.
但我的裙子。上面有血。
- I must go back and change.
- No, you can't do that.
- 我一定要回去把它换掉。
- 不，你不能这样做。
Or I could go myself.
或许我一个人去。
Oh, darling, could you?
There's no one there.
噢，打令，你可以吗？
这里没有其他人了。
I'd give you the key.
我把钥匙给你。
There's a blue dress like this
in the big cupboard...
在大衣柜里有一条好像这样蓝色的裙子…
...next to my window in the bedroom.
Here's the key.
…就在我睡房窗户旁边。这是钥匙。
- Are you sure the servants aren't back?
- No, but you must hurry. Oh, please, Jonnie.
- 你肯定佣人不会回来？
- 是，但你要快点。噢，麻烦你，Jonnie。
This is my only chance.
这是我唯一的机会。
- You will, won't you?
- It's a risk.
- 你可以的，是吗？
- 这是冒险。
Let me think a minute. I mean...
让我想一下。我的意思…
Well, you know I want to help you, but...
好吧，你也知道我想帮你，但…
Go or don't go. It's all the same.
去与不去。都是一样。
I thought you loved me.
我以为你是爱我的。
- Doesn't matter now.
- Oh, my dear. My darling.
- 现在已经不重要了。
- 噢，亲爱的。我的打令。
I'd do anything for you. You know that.
我可以为你做任何事。你是知道的。
I'll be as quick as I can.
我一定会尽快的。
It was your maid, Nellie.
是你的佣人，Nellie。
Oh, yes.
噢，是呀。
She was going to the house to pick up
some shoes I need for the show.
她要去屋子里拿我表演用的鞋子。
- Did she recognize you?
- I don't know.
- 她认得你吗？
- 我不知道。
You ought to get to the theater. The police
are bound to go there to tell you the news.
你一定要赶快去剧院。
警察马上会到那里通知你这消息。
Give me my belt, darling, will you?
把带子给我，打令，好吗？
Oh, Jonnie, what have I done to you?
噢，Jonnie，看我把你害成怎样？
If Nellie recognized you,
it won't be safe here.
如果Nellie认出你，这里是不安全的。
- You ought to go away.
- I don't think that'll do much good.
- 你要赶紧走。
- 我不认为有什么帮助。
But they'll come here.
You must go at once.
但他们会来这里。你要马上走。
Oh, my dearest darling,
you have saved me.
噢，我最亲爱的打令，你救了我。
We must think of you now.
You've got to hide.
我们现在要为你想想。你一定要躲起来。
What do I care what happens to me?
我还会在乎我将会怎样？
Your job is to try to forget everything.
你现在的责任是要忘记这一切。
Let me do the worrying. I'll find a way.
让我来处理。我会想到办法的。
Then we'll start again,
won't we, you and I?
我们会从新开始，会吗，你跟我？
No more stealth and cheating and lying.
不用再偷偷摸摸和说谎。
I must hurry, darling.
But I worry about you.
我一定要赶快，打令。但我担心你。
Well, you mustn't. You're an actress.
You're playing a part.
可是，你不可以。你是个演员。
你现在要演你的角色。
- No nerves when you're on.
- I'll try.
- 你当上就不能紧张。
- 我会尽量。
My dress!
我的裙子！
- I'll get rid of that. Don't worry.
- Don't come down.
- 我会把它弄走。不用担心。
- 不要下来。
We shouldn't be seen together.
我们不能给人看见我们在一起。
- Au revoir, my darling.
- Au revoir.
- Au revoir，打令。
And for heaven's sake, don't worry.
看在老天爷份上，不要担心。
- Yes?
- May I speak to Miss Eve Gill, please?
- 怎么事？
- 请问，我可以跟Eve Gill小姐谈一下吗？
Oh, dear, no. I'm afraid she isn't in.
噢，亲爱的，不行。她还没有到。
She was going for the weekend
to her father...
她去了她父亲那里渡周末…
...but I thought she'd be back.
- Yes, that's right. She got back last night.
…但我想她快回来。
- 哦，对了。她昨晚回来了。
She's had rehearsals all day today
at the Royal Academy of Dramatic Art.
她今天整天需要在皇家戏剧学院彩排。
You know, the RADA.
你知道的，是RADA。
Do you know when she...?
Where she is now?
你知道她什么时候…？
她现在在那？
Didn't you hear?
你没有听说吗？
She's at the RADA rehearsing.
她在RADA彩排。
- Jonathan Cooper?
- Yes.
- 是Jonathan Cooper吗？
- 是。
We're police officers.
May we see you for a few minutes?
我们是警察。可以耽误你几分钟吗？
Most certainly. Please come in.
当然可以。请进。
- Tell you that I can't possibly
accede to your request.
- 可以告诉你我不可能答应你的要求。
I've come to this decision after giving
the matter my earnest consideration.
我是经过非常慎重的考虑才作出这决定。
Stop me if ever there was
such an ungrateful child!
阻止我如果你觉得我是个坏孩子！
No, darling. Don't run your words
into one another.
不，打令。不要说得太快。
- The child most shamefully.
- 一个最可耻的孩子。
Is it not in your memory
that we, too, years ago...
你还记得我们，同样，两年前…
...suffered the follies and fevers of youth?
…寻迷在年青人的无知与狂热？
If our blood runs cooler
and more temperate, let us not account...
如果我们已经冷静可以自控，
我们就不要考虑…
...to ourselves for virtue, but place it
to the credit of the soothing balm...
…道德观点，应考虑所给与的平静…
...of the passage of years
that we have fortifications...
…和这几年里我们的枷锁压抑…
...against the distempers of juvenility.
…面对这年少时的错误。
You were wont to be kinder than this.
你应该得到更好的对待。
No, Papa, you are cruel.
If all parents were of your mind...
不，爸爸，你太残忍了。
如果每对父母的想法跟你一样…
...marriage would be an impossibility. Then
what would become of the human race?
…就不可能有婚姻。人类会变成怎样？
- Go away. What are you doing here?
- The police are after me. Do you see them?
- 走吧。你在这里干吗？
- 警察在找我。你有没有看见他们？
You have not, I hope,
forgotten the tragedy...
我希望，你没有，忘记那惨剧…
They think I killed a man.
Can you hide me on your father's boat?
他们以为我杀了人。你可把我藏在你爸的船吗？
Are you so heartless as to wish...?
你是否没心没肺的去想…？
They've just gone.
他们才刚走。
I was under the impression that this
was a class of intelligent students...
我还以为这是一班聪明的学生…
...trying to master an extremely
difficult and beautiful art.
…努力去克服困难和艺术。
I haven't the pleasure of knowing you,
young man...
认识你真是没有一点荣幸，年青人…
...but I shall report your behavior
to Sir Kenneth.
…但我会告诉Sir Kenneth你的行为。
Now we will begin the rehearsal again,
with the other cast.
现在我们继续彩排，跟另一组角色。
- This cast think acting is fun and games.
- I'm terribly sorry, Miss Ashton.
- 那一组以为演戏是好玩和游戏。
- 真是对不起，Ashton小姐。
- Oh, Jonathan.
- Let's go. Have you got your car here?
- 噢，Jonathan。
- 我们走吧。你有开车来吗？
It's parked in front. I'll show you
to the back entrance and pick you up there.
它停在前面。我带你到后门就在能里接你。
Eve, do you hate me...
Eve，你恨我吗…
...now that you know
about Charlotte and me?
…你现在知道我和Charlotte的事？
Why, I could never hate you, Jonathan...
为什么，我不可能恨你的，Jonathan…
...because we're...
We're such old friends.
…因为我们是…
我们是老朋友。
And...
而且…
Well, just because.
唔，只有这原因。
But I do wish I'd taken lessons
on the second fiddle.
但我希望下次会学乖。
Good old Eve.
我的Eve。
Bring him in here.
带他进来。
It's warmer.
这里暖和些。
Do you think I behaved like a fool?
你觉得我是个傻瓜吗？
On the whole, I think so.
整体来说，我认为是。
I think your boyfriend
has behaved like a fool.
我觉得你男朋友是个傻瓜。
I have a strong premonition
that I'm going to behave like a fool.
我有不祥的预感我将会是个傻瓜。
- It's infectious.
- Do you mean you're going to help him?
- 这是会感染的。
- 你的意思是你会帮他？
Why not?
为什么不帮？
He's a friend of yours, isn't he?
他是你朋友，不是吗？
- Oh, yes.
- I see.
- 噢，是的。
- 我明白了。
More than a friend, eh?
不单是朋友，哦？
When I'm with him, I get a feeling
in here that... That's sort of...
跟他在一起，我这里有种感觉…是那种…
Yes. Well, we'll go
into the symptoms later.
是。好吧，我们晚些才讨论你这症状。
Meanwhile, I take it you're either
keen on him or still hungry.
目前，我就看成是有兴趣或是肚子饿吧。
I'm in love with him.
我爱上他了。
You've roped him, but he's not yet
broken to harness. Is that it?
你绑住他，但他还没有完全放开怀抱。是不是？
I wish Charlotte Inwood was in...
我希望Charlotte Inwood还在…
Oh, do you?
噢，真的？
I've seen her on the stage.
我在台上看见她。
She'd have made me laugh,
if I hadn't been strictly on my guard.
如果我不是认真的岗位上，她会让我笑出来。
Well, she couldn't make me laugh,
off or on the stage.
可是，她不能让我笑，不管在台上或台下。
I can't bear to sit by and see
what she's doing to Jonathan.
我真的忍不住看她怎样对Jonathan。
She's like an evil spirit.
Just look at him!
她就像个魔鬼。看看他！
Ruined, and by a woman.
被一个女人，害的多惨。
Now you want me to take the ruins
for a little cruise.
你现在想我带这被害人去流浪一下。
- Well, is that it?
- I thought you could take him...
- 哦，就是这样？
- 我以为你能带他…
...across the channel or to the Irish coast.
Then he could hide out a bit.
…穿过水道或是到爱尔兰海岸。
然后他可以躲一会。
The journey sounds attractive,
but less so...
这行程蛮吸引的，但好像是…
...to help a suspected murderer to escape,
particularly with my reputation.
…协助杀人嫌疑犯逃走，
尤其是以我的形象。
There's nothing wrong
with your reputation.
你的形象没什么问题。
Oh, indeed.
I rather flattered myself that there was.
噢，是吗。我也希望自己相信是这样。
As a matter of fact, the customs people
have their eye on me.
可是事实上，那些海关的人总盯着我。
I'm suspected of being a smuggler.
我被怀疑是走私客。
- Well, you're not.
- Oh, yes, I am.
- 可是，你不是。
- 噢，是，我是。
One cask of brandy?
That doesn't mean you're a smuggler.
一桶白兰地？这不代表你是走私客。
- Two casks.
- That was 15 years ago.
- 两桶。
- 那是15年前的事。
I've done one or two other things since
that I didn't tell you or your mother about.
我还干过一两次其他的只是没有告诉你或你母亲。
- Can't have been very much.
- Of course not. Not very much.
- 也不是什么大事。
- 但然不是。不是什么大事。
Nothing could appear very much
to a murderer's moll.
跟谋杀共犯比当然算不上是什么大事。
But I never hope to be appreciated.
但我也不会希望别人欣赏这些。
Yes, your mother cured me of that.
对，是你母亲把我治好的。
That's why I never could be bothered
with your mother.
所以我也不会麻烦你母亲。
I appreciate you, Father. You and
Captain Kidd are my favorite heroes.
我感谢你，爸爸。你和Kidd船长是我最爱的英雄。
My child, I am not deceived.
我的孩子，我不是误导你。
If there's one thing I cannot bear,
it's insincerity.
我最不能忍受的事，是不诚实。
But you've got to help him.
You will help him, won't you?
但你一定要帮他。你会帮他的，会吗？
He's lonely. He hasn't got any friends
but me, and maybe you.
你很寂寞。除了我可能还有你，他没有朋友。
- You will help him, won't you?
- He hasn't got me...
- 你会帮他的，会吗？
- 他没跟我…
...yet.
…还没。
You're just dying to get into a part of this,
and you know you are.
你求之不得参与此事，你自己也知道的。
A part in this melodramatic play,
you mean?
你是说，参与这夸张的戏剧性演出？
That's the way you're treating it, Eve.
你是这样看的，Eve。
As though it were a play
you were acting in at the Academy.
虽然这只是演戏，但你是在学院里演出啊。
Everything seems a fine acting role
when you're stage-struck...
只要你热爱演出各方面看这都是个好角色…
...doesn't it, my dear?
…不是吗，亲爱的？
Here you have a plot,
an interesting cast...
这是你的剧本，非常有趣的角色…
...even a costume,
little the worse for wear.
…还有戏服，有点忙不过来。
Unfortunately, Eve,
in this real and earnest life...
非常不幸，Eve，在这现实的生活中…
...we must face the situation
and all its bearings.
…我们必须面对这种情况和成担。
Yes.
对。
What do you mean?
你是什么意思？
Well, Miss Charlotte Inwood
appears to be an expert in garden paths.
这样，Charlotte Inwood小姐
好像是公园小径的专家。
I think she's led your young friend
up the garden path.
我想她带你的年青朋友去公园小径。
I think we should hesitate
before we follow him.
我想我们应该考虑清楚才跟他走。
- But why?
- I don't know how this bloodstain...
- 但为什么？
- 我不知道这血迹怎会…
...got onto this dress, but I do know that
somebody smeared it on deliberately.
…沾在这裙子上，但我知道是有人故意擦上去。
But why should they do that?
但是他们为什么要这样做？
Well, Miss Inwood is an actress,
a very good one.
唔，Inwood小姐是演员，一个有名的演员。
She has an eye
for an emotional situation.
她的感情状况很多人关注。
Supposing she wanted our somnolent
young friend to go to her house...
假如她想她的秘密年青朋友去她家…
...and be spotted there.
…被发现了。
Well, this sanguinary garment
would provide a very plausible reason.
这染血的衣服提供了一个非常有说服力的原因。
A very plausible reason indeed.
确实是个非常有说服力的原因。
So that's why she didn't change her dress
before she went to his rooms.
这就是为什么她过来前不把裙子换掉。
Well, I cannot imagine Miss Inwood
going to see her young man...
我不能假设Inwood小姐会去见她那小伙子。
Or your young man, whose ever young man
he is, in this nasty, messy condition.
或你那小伙子，不管他是谁的小伙子，
在这坏透，又混乱的情况下。
No. This dress is a clue, my dear,
a very important clue.
不。这裙子是线索，亲爱的，是个重要线索。
And though it grieves me, of all people,
to have to say it, Eve...
虽然这让我很难过，所有人，也会这样说，Eve…
...I think we should go to the police.
…我想我们一定要去找警察。
Jonathan! Jonathan, wake up.
Jonathan！Jonathan，起来。
Jonathan, how far do you think
you could trust Charlotte?
Jonathan，你想你能相信Charlotte到那程度？
I'd trust her with my life.
What do you mean?
我可以把性命交给她。你是什么意思？
This bloodstain was put here deliberately.
这血迹是有意弄上去的。
Don't be ridiculous. You're trying to turn me
against Charlotte, but you can't.
别荒谬。你想要我指正Charlotte，不可能。
What's this doing here, anyhow?
It should have been destroyed hours ago!
留着这东西还有什么用？
应该一早就把它毁灭！
Fool! There goes the evidence
that could've helped you.
笨蛋！这里有证据可能会帮到你。
I'm doing all this for Charlotte's sake.
You're just jealous of her!
我做这一切都是为了Charlotte。你只是嫉妒她！
Young man, I'd remind you
you're my daughter's guest.
年青人，我要提醒你，你是我女儿的客人。
I'd like better manners from you.
我觉得你的态度应该好些。
Oh, I am sorry, Eve.
噢，对不起，Eve。
Please forgive me.
请原谅我。
I lost my head for a moment.
我一时失态了。
I can hardly think.
I'm almost dead for want of sleep.
我很难想象。为了睡一觉我差点死了。
I wonder, would it be too much trouble
if I went to bed?
好奇怪，我去睡觉是不是会带来很大麻烦？
That is, if Commodore Gill
wants to let me stay.
会的，如果Gill指挥官要我留下。
Your room is at the head of the stairs.
You'll be quite comfortable.
你的房间在楼梯的尽头。你会挺舒服的。
And if you want anything to read in bed...
如果你想睡前看书…
...you'll find some quite good
murder mysteries in there.
…你会在那找到些挺好的谋杀小说。
Beg your pardon.
你说什么。
Look, Eve...
你看，Eve…
But he's just gone...
但他刚走…
At last we are alone and unobserved.
You know, I'm beginning to enjoy this.
起码没人还有没被发现。
你知道吗，我开始有点喜欢这样。
Father, do you think she arranged
to put the suspicion on Jonathan?
爸，你认为是她安排让Jonathan受嫌疑的吗？
- Do you think she deliberately framed him?
- The thought had crossed my mind.
- 你认为是她故意陷害他吗？
- 我总是这样想。
That was why I reluctantly suggested that
our friends, the police, ought to be told.
所以我不愿意提议我们的朋友，应该告诉警察。
But it's too late. Our only evidence
has gone up the chimney.
但现在太晚了。我们唯一的证据已经烧掉。
But we must help him.
He'll do nothing for himself.
但我们一定要帮他。你不会为自己做任何事。
He's hopelessly in love with that woman.
It's up to us.
他已经无可救药的迷恋那女人。只有靠我们了。
Yes, but it won't be easy.
对，但不会容易。
It is easy.
I'll go to her and see her myself.
很容易。我会亲自去见她。
- Would that be wise?
- But I don't care if it is or not.
- 这样做是明智吗？
- 但我不管是不是？
I'll tell her we know how the bloodstain got
on the dress and every move of her game.
我会告诉她我们知道那血迹怎会在裙子上
和她那游戏的每一步。
I'll make her talk.
It'll be one woman to another.
我会逼她说出来。这是两个女人之间的事。
An impressive situation at any time.
任何时候这都是精彩的状况。
She won't be able to help
but give herself away. You'll see.
她将会无计可施只有交待。你看着吧。
I won't see. I won't be there,
and neither will you.
我看不到。我不会在那，你也不可以。
If we're right in what we think,
she's a dangerous woman.
如果我们所想的是对的，她是个危险的女人。
She won't give herself away.
You'd be giving her an alternative.
她不会交待。你会给她另一选择。
She has no alternative.
她没有别的选择。
She might murder you.
她可能把你谋杀。
Oh, don't be so melodramatic, Father.
噢，不要想得太戏剧性，爸爸。
Look, my love. Face facts.
看清楚，亲爱的。面对事实。
What is the least that can happen to you
if you tackle this remarkable lady?
如果你去接触这厉害的女士，
你最幸运会是怎样？
She'll at once pick up a little pink
telephone and call the police.
她会马上拿起那粉红色的小电话去找警察。
She will then give you in charge
for concealing a fugitive from justice.
她会告发你隐藏逃犯。
Eventually, you will be tried
at the Old Bailey.
最后，你会在Old Bailey被审问。
Well, if you're lucky, you might get off
with, now, let me see...
嗯，如果你幸运，你会脱罪，现在，让我想想…
...a couple of years, which you will spend
in Holloway prison...
…几年吧，你会在Holloway监狱度过…
...meditating on the folly of transmuting
melodrama into real life.
…理性的想想把愚蠢的戏剧情节回到现实。
Well...
嗯…
The best thing you can do, my girl,
is to go back to your Academy...
我的小女孩，现在最好是先回你的学院去…
...and practice your soul-shaking antics...
…表现你那激动的举止…
...in surroundings where
they can't do any harm.
…在公众场所他们不能伤害你。
After all, this fellow can't possibly
mean all that to you.
不管怎样，这小伙子不可能是你的一切。
But he does, Father.
但他是，爸爸。
- Move along, please.
- But I'd like...
- 请你去吧。
- 但我想…
Now move along, ma'am.
This is nothing to see.
马上去吧，大姐。没什么好看。
Hello, Father?
I'm outside the Inwood house.
喂，爸爸？我在Inwood家外面。
Outside? Why not inside?
在外面？为什么不进去？
Don't be ridiculous, Father.
The police won't let anyone near the place.
不要荒谬吧，爸爸。警察不会让任何人接近。
Really? How very extraordinary.
是吗？真不寻常。
Look, you've done your best.
Come back here...
看，你已经尽力了。回来吧…
...and decide about the man
that came to dinner.
…为昨晚来吃饭那人再想想。
Oh, I feel awful. I've been listening
to the people in the crowd talking...
噢，我觉得很难受。我听见人们在说…
...and they assume that
you-know-who is guilty...
…你知道他们认定谁是有罪…
...and all the police have to do
is catch him. It's terrifying.
…而所有警察都要抓他。真可怕。
Yes, but the police may not
think he's guilty.
是，但警察不一定认为他有罪。
After all, they work in secret, you know.
不管怎样，他们是秘密行事，你也知道。
They may have their own ideas
about a certain lady.
他们可能对某女士有些想法。
I wish I knew what
the police were thinking.
我希望我知道警察在想什么。
- Well, look, why not ask them?
- Well, that's easier said than done.
- 嗯，为什么不问他们？
- 唔，说比做容易。
Oh, just a minute, Father.
噢，等一下，爸爸。
- Father, goodbye now.
- Eve...
- 爸爸，就这样吧。
- Eve…
I'll see you back at the office
about 2:00, sir.
将官，我2:00左右回办公室，到时见。
May I have a small brandy, please?
可以给我一小杯白兰地，好吗？
Madam. Pardon my intrusion,
but is there, by any chance...
太太。打扰了，但有没有机会，有什么…
...any assistance I could be of?
- No, thank you.
…我能帮上忙？
- 不用了，谢谢。
- I don't know how you pick up all the dirt.
- Oh, I get around.
- 我不明白你在那沾上那么多灰尘。
- 噢，我传了一会。
Any case, I know Munson's...
无论如何，我了解Munson…
Right from the horse's mouth.
从头到脚的彻底了解。
I most solemnly assure you, madam...
我极小的这样保证，太太…
...it would be a pleasure, if there was
any assistance I could be of.
…如果有什么可以帮上，将会是我的荣誉。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢你。
If you will allow me to say so,
you look depressed.
请容许我这样说，你好像很不开心。
Yes, the cheering word,
the helping hand...
对，是鼓励的话，是好帮手…
I'm perfectly all right.
我真的没事。
Oh, good. Right. Good, good.
噢，很好。没事。好，好。
Is there anything I can do?
我可以为你做什么吗？
Look, I don't know your trouble,
but you don't look very well to me.
你看，我不知道你有什么麻烦，
但你看来不是很好。
A little brandy can't do you any harm.
Why not drink it?
一小杯白兰地不会对你有害。为什么不喝？
My great-aunt died over a glass of brandy,
but it was her 15th that day.
我的曾姨妈喝了一杯白兰地就死了，
不过那是她那天的第15杯。
- Feeling any better?
- Yes, thank you.
- 感觉好点没有？
- 是，谢谢。
You left your lunch over there.
你的午餐留在这里。
It won't feel lonely.
I'll go back to it in a minute.
它会感到孤单。我等一下就回去。
Perhaps you're allergic to bars.
Look...
或许你对酒吧敏感。你看…
...would you feel less uneasy
if I sat with you, or more so?
…如果我陪你伤心或比你更伤心，
你会不会感觉好点？
- Perhaps you're allergic to strange men too.
- No. I love strange men.
- 或许你对陌生男人也敏感吧。
- 不。我爱陌生男人。
- I mean, I'm very fond of them.
- I'll just go and get my lunch.
- 我的意思是，我很喜欢他们。
- 我还是去拿我的午餐。
The butler told me. Never saw such a sight.
They say his head was bashed in.
那管家告诉我。不要看这种事。
他们说他的头受重击。
I heard they clocked him so hard his
false teeth went across the room.
我听说他们太用力打他连他的假牙都打掉。
I know I'm pretty silly, but I overheard
two people on the street today...
我知道我挺笨的，
但我今天无意间听到两人在街上说…
...talking about the murder.
…关于那凶杀案。
They went into a lot of detail.
他们说到很多细节。
I felt so sick and giddy,
I just had to come in and have a brandy.
我觉得很不舒服又晕，我需要进来喝杯白兰地。
My father says I tend
to overdramatize everything.
我爸说我把什么都想得太戏剧性。
I expect he's right. I know how you feel,
though. I hate violence myself.
我想他是对的。需然我知道你怎样想。
我个人是讨厌暴力。
Doesn't that make it
rather difficult for you?
这会让你很为难吗？
I mean, I think we ought to face up
to the ugly side of life.
我的意思是，我们必须面对人生丑恶的一面。
Now, me, for instance.
I'm an actress.
现在，比方说，我。我是个演员。
I ought to face up to all sorts
of experiences, oughtn't I?
我必须面对各种的经验，不是吗？
Oh, I don't know. Supposing I happened
to be a librarian.
噢，我不知道。比如说我是个图书馆职员。
A librarian doesn't encounter much violence
except an occasional encyclopedia falling.
一个图书馆职员不会面对太多暴力
只是偶尔会有百科全书掉下。
But you're not a librarian, are you?
但你不是图书馆职员，是吗？
No, I'm not. How do you know?
不，我不是。你怎会知道？
Well, you just don't
look like a librarian.
唔，你就是不像个图书馆职员
- You don't look like an actress.
- Oh? I thought I did.
- 你不像个演员。
- 哦？我以为我想。
Well, I'm only a beginner, really.
That is, I've only played one part in public.
唔，我只是个初哥，真的。
就是说，我只公开演出过一次。
- Could I have seen you?
- I don't think so.
- 我曾经见过你吗？
- 应该没有。
It was in the church hall.
I played the fourth deadly sin.
在教堂里。我演出第四种死罪。
- Were you good?
- I was pretty deadly.
- 你演得好吗？
- 我就想死尸。
What was this Jonathan Cooper after?
这个Jonathan Cooper想要什么？
- I heard there was nothing stolen.
- Perhaps he did it for the fun of it...
- 我听说没有东西被偷。
- 可能他干这个是为了乐趣…
Poor Charlotte Inwood.
可怜的Charlotte Inwood。
Imagine coming home and finding
your husband horribly dead...
想像一下回家发现自己丈夫可怕的死去…
...policemen and detectives
all over the house, and the blood...
…满屋子都是警察和侦探，还有血…
Careful, careful.
小心，小心。
Remember, you're sensitive to that sort
of thing. You'll bring on another fainting fit.
记住，你对这些事挺敏感的。你会再次昏倒。
I hear that Charlotte Inwood's going back
into the show in a couple of days.
我听说Charlotte Inwood过两天会再次演出。
Must be dreadful to sing and dance...
要唱歌跳舞一定很难受…
...with that horrible picture
still burning in one's mind.
…尤其是那可怕的阴影还在脑海。
Oh, it's the old story, "Is not the actor
the man with a heart?" all over again.
噢，是个旧故事，
“不是演员他是有心人？”再重演。
I once had a cousin
who had a duodenal ulcer...
我有个外甥他患了十二指肠溃疡…
...and an extremely funny face,
both at the same time.
…同时也有张有趣的脸。
Everybody laughed
when he was telling his symptoms.
当他说出他的病状每个人都在笑。
His name was Jim.
他叫Jim。
That must have been terrible.
那一定是很糟。
Oh, I don't know.
Jim's quite a common name.
噢，我不知道。Jim是个很普通的名字。
I wonder what Charlotte Inwood
is really like. Really, I mean.
我在想Charlotte Inwood是什么毛样的。
真的，我很认真。
- Oh, hello, Nellie.
- That's Charlotte Inwood's maid.
- 噢，你好，Nellie。
- 她是Charlotte Inwood的佣人。
Hello, Nellie. I didn't expect
to see you so soon.
你好，Nellie。想不到这么快见到你。
How are you bearing up after last night?
经过昨晚你怎样忍受这一切？
Mrs. Tippet, what I've been through.
All those policemen.
Tippet太太，我所经历的一切。所有警察。
Bothering you with a lot of questions.
烦扰你的许多问题。
Questions? They've been asking me this,
asking me that, all morning long.
问题？他们整个早上，问我这个那个的。
I didn't know whether
I was coming or going.
我不知道我应该去或留。
Gin and lemon, please, Mrs. Tippet.
Gin酒加柠檬，好吗，Tippet太太。
- Not too much lemon, dear.
- Okay.
- 不要太多柠檬，亲爱的。
- OK。
Mind you, they never laid a finger on me,
but, oh, the questions. Nag, nag, nag.
提醒你，他们没碰我，但是，
噢，那些问题。别，别，别。
"How did you know it was Mr. Cooper?
How many times you seen him and where?
“你怎样知道是Cooper先生？
你见过他多少次在那？
And did he give you anything?"
Blimey, he never gave me nothing.
还有他有给你什么吗？”
Blimey，他从来也没有给我什么。
"And how long you been
Miss Inwood's maid?"
“你当Inwood小姐的佣人有多久？”
They was gentlemanly and polite,
all right...
他们很有礼又有礼貌，好吗…
...but give me the bleeding Russians
any day, dear.
…但每天给我那可恨的苏联人，亲爱的。
Yes. You gotta watch your step
when you're up against the police.
对。当我们要对付警察时你要小心奕点。
If that wasn't enough,
when I came out of the house...
如果当我离开房子，那还不够…
...the reporters pounced on me with their
questions, asking me the lowdown.
…记者们会跳出来提问，问我些尖锐的。
I just jumped out of my skin when that
photographer's flashbulb went.
那摄影师的闪光灯刚把我吓了一跳。
Well, I mean, fancy taking my picture.
唔，我的意思是，未经同意给我拍照。
You're quite a celebrity, you lucky girl.
I'll have to buy the Daily Mirror tomorrow.
你应该庆祝，幸运的小姑娘。
我明天一定要买每日镜报
Of course, I'm not saying a word
to the reporters. Not a word.
当然，我对记者什么也没说。一个字也没有。
After all, who discovered the body?
说到底，谁发现尸体？
I'll be a star witness at that trial, and my
story ought to be worth something...
在审讯中我将会是个名星证人，
我的故事应该有些价值…
...and I've no intention of giving it away.
…而且我没打算放弃。
- Isn't she talking too much?
- Too much, too loud, too everything.
- 她是否说得太多？
- 太多，太吵，什么都太多。
How do you feel now?
你现在感觉怎样？
Oh, I feel a little better, thank you.
噢，我感觉好点了，谢谢。
I have to go.
我要走了。
I don't like leaving you here alone.
我不想剩下你一个人在这。
Do you feel fit enough
to let me see you home?
我去你家见你你觉得合适吗？
- I have a car.
- Perhaps you'd better let me drive it for you.
- 我有开车来。
- 或许让我替你开车会好点。
Well, that's very kind of you.
I do still feel a bit wobbly.
唔，你真好人。我真的还觉得有点发抖。
To be quite honest, it isn't kindness at all.
I mean, I'm afraid I maneuvered it.
老实说，这不是什么好。
我的意思是，我怕我令到你这样。
How clever of you.
你真聪明。
You've got something there, Fred.
I'll drink to that, on you.
Fred你有些东西在那。我会喝了它，为了你。
A double gin and lemon, please.
双份的gin酒加柠檬，麻烦你。
Double? All right, Nellie,
I hope it chokes you.
双份？好吧，Nellie，希望把你呛到。
You don't miss a trick, do you?
You're always on the make.
你不会放过任何机会损人，是不是？?
你常常这样做。
My mother's really a dear. My father, too,
but they shout at one another...
我母亲很可爱。
我父亲，一样可爱，但他们常对骂…
...and neither one like to shout.
…可是他们都不喜欢吵架。
I can't tell you
how much I appreciate this.
我说不出我是多么感谢。
You've been extraordinarily kind and
you know nothing whatsoever about me.
你实在是太好了而年根本不了解我。
Oh, I don't know, Miss Gill.
噢，我不知道，Gill小姐。
You were born in South Africa.
The 17th of September, wasn't it?
你在南非出生。9月17号，是不是？
Educated in America and you're studying
at the Royal Academy of Dramatic Art.
在美国受教育是在皇家戏剧学院。
Your parents don't live together.
你双亲住在一起。
You're a very well-behaved lady, but allergic
to murder, and that drove you to drink.
你是个很有礼貌的淑女，
但对谋杀敏感，使你喝酒。
I hope it's only temporary.
希望是暂时性的。
But I don't even know your name.
但我连你名字都不知道。
I only know that you play the piano.
我只知道你是玩钢琴的。
I'm so sorry. It was stupid of me.
I forgot. My name is Smith.
对不起。我太苯了。我忘了。我叫Smith。
Just ordinary Smith?
只是普通的Smith？
A detective?
是侦探？
I hope you don't mind.
希望你不介意。
Oh, no. Of course not.
噢，不会。当然不会。
Well, I'm delighted.
嗯，我很欣慰。
By the way, I don't suppose you and
your mother are interested in tea...
说回来，我想你和你母亲想喝点茶…
...with a detective, that is.
…跟一个侦探，这是。
Of course. Especially with a detective.
当然。尤其是侦探。
- Would you like to have tea with us?
- Oh, I'd love to. How about this afternoon?
- 你想跟我们喝杯茶吗？
- 噢，我非常愿意。这个下午好吗？
- Well, tomorrow, then?
- Yes.
- 那，明天吧？
- 好。
Yes. That's fine.
好。可以。
And I could take your place.
我可以去你哪里。
You'd never get away with it. What
makes you think you could be a maid?
你永远忘不了。什么让你想成为女佣？
It would only be for a day or two.
只是一两天。
You'd have to be her dresser
down at the theater.
你本来是她在剧院的服装师。
You couldn't do that.
That's very highly skilled work.
你不能做那些。那是很尊业的工作。
- Well, I could if you told me how.
- It sounds phony to me.
- 哦，如果你教我我是可以的。
- 听起来好像很虚伪。
All this trouble just to get
a newspaper story.
这些麻烦只不过是要上报。
Well, we women reporters have
a tough job competing with the men...
嗯，做女记者在男人堆里是件艰苦的工作…
...especially on
important stories like this.
…尤其是这种大新闻。
And what paper are you on, may I ask?
你是那份报纸的,我可以问吗？
Well, I can't tell you that.
嗯，我不能告诉你。
If anything should go wrong,
it would be embarrassing for the paper.
如果有什么差错，会让报社尴尬。
Oh? And what about my job?
噢？那我的工作呢？
Suppose Miss Inwood found out
I was passing you off as my cousin.
如果Inwood小姐知道我因为外甥而透露资料。
I'm not sure she won't smell a rat.
我不能肯定她不会发现。
I never been away ill for years.
我没试过请几年病假。
But anyone could go sick.
And I could do it, really I could.
但每个人都会病。而且我会这样做，真的会。
I've... I've done a bit of acting.
我…我也演过一点戏。
Character acting?
演角色？
- Yes.
- I see.
- 是。
- 我明白了。
All you gotta do is put on some old clothes
and make yourself look common like me.
你要做的只是穿上些旧衣服像我一样普通。
Let me explain why it's so important
that I get the right slant on this.
让我解释为什么我要冒这个险。
I think there's a romance between
Miss Inwood and this man named Cooper.
我想Inwood小姐跟那个叫Cooper的男人有恋情。
And where did you get this idea?
Do you know what I think?
你凭什么有这想法？
你知道我怎样想？
- I think you're snooping for the police.
- Oh, no...
- 我想你是替警察做监视。
- 噢，不…
I saw you this morning sitting
on this very seat with a detective.
今天早上我看见你跟一个侦探坐在这。
Oh, well, that was Wilfred Smith.
噢，是，那是Wilfred Smith。
He's an old friend of mine.
I didn't get a thing out of him.
他是我一个老朋友。我在他身上什么也没得到。
Charlie, double gin and lemon, please.
Charlie，双份gin酒加柠檬，麻烦你。
- Not too much lemon, dear.
- Same for me.
- 不要太多柠檬，亲爱的。
- 我也一样。
I can get five times that much
from any newspaper when the case is over.
当这案子完了我可以在报社拿到多五倍的。
Why not get both?
为什么不两边都要？
Caught you, have I?
抓到你了，有没有？
Hope I don't intrude
on some deep conspiracy.
但愿我不会被迫卷入大阴谋中。
And I hope you find yourself no worse
for your distressing experiences.
我也希望你会发现你的顾虑是多余的。
Haven't I met your charming
friend before? I know that face.
我有见过你这漂亮的朋友吗？我觉得很面善。
This is my cousin Doris, Mr. Fortesque.
这是我外甥Doris，Fortesque先生。
Oh, yeah. Charming. Charming.
噢，是啊。漂亮。漂亮。
Perhaps as dear Nellie didn't
provide me with your surname...
或许亲爱的Nellie没有告诉我你姓什么…
...you'll let me call you Doris, eh?
…你可以告诉我Doris，嗯？
Mrs. Mason, I can't think what I've done
with my reading glasses.
Mason小姐，我想不到我的眼镜放那。
Have you seen them anywhere?
你有没有在哪里看见？
- Could l...?
- Oh, there you are.
- 我可否…？
- 噢，在这里。
Help me find my glasses, Eve, darling.
I can't see a thing.
替我找一下我的眼镜，Eve，亲爱的。
我看不道东西。
I'm Doris Tinsdale.
我是Doris Tinsdale。
I'm from Nellie.
是Nellie那边的。
Move along there, please.
过去那边，麻烦你。
I'm Doris Tinsdale.
我是Doris Tinsdale。
- Miss Inwood's expecting me.
- Oh, yes.
- Inwood小姐知道我来的。
- 噢，对。
You're the temporary Nellie sent along.
你是Nettie介绍过来的临时工。
Just wait over here a minute.
在这里等一会。
We'd like to see Miss Inwood.
Can I have a few words with you as well?
我想见Inwood小姐。我可以跟你说几句吗？
By all means.
Will you step this way, please?
没问题。请这边走，好吗？
I understand you've been in service
now for six or seven years.
我知道你在这里已经服务了六或七年。
Six years and nine months,
to be precise...
准确来说，是六年九个月…
Come in.
进来。
Okay, yes. I'll come around
the box office tonight.
OK，是。我今晚会到售票处。
- What did they say, Freddie?
- More cancellations.
- 他们怎样说，Freddie？
- 更多取消。
Oh, how stupid people are.
噢，人们真笨。
Even if my understudy's legs
are so peculiar...
就是我的候补也是不赖…
...she's just as good as I am.
…她跟我一样好。
She knows darn well she'd better not be.
That's not the point.
她很清楚她最好不要。
这不是问题所在。
It's you they want to see.
他们想要看的是你。
- Well, what do you want?
- I'm from Nellie.
- 嗯，你想怎样？
- 是Nellie让我来的。
Madam's expecting me.
夫人知道我会来。
The new girl's here, Charlie.
新来的女孩到了，Charlie。
No, no. This doesn't fit me.
不，不。这个我不合适。
Here, here. Pull it up on this side.
The other side too.
这里，这里。在这边拉高。那边也一样。
You know that, don't you?
你知道的，是不是？
Excuse me, madam.
对不起，夫人。
Read it to me, dear.
读给我听，亲爱的。
"Dear Madam, this will introduce
my cousin Doris...
“亲爱的夫人，这是介绍我外甥Doris…
...who is in every way a good girl."
…她是各方面都很好的女孩。”
Not so loud.
不要太大声。
"I hope you'll find her satisfactory
during my illness. Signed, Nellie Goode."
“在我生病期间我希望你对她满意。
Nellie Goode签字。”
This is very nice,
if you can call mourning nice...
这非常好，如果你早上先打电话来…
...but isn't there some way we could let it
plunge a little in front? I suppose not.
…但不是可以预先通知？我认为不应该。
"Signed, Nellie Goode."
“Nellie Goode签字”
If we could only work in a little
color somewhere. Oh, well.
我希望我们可以在那里加点色彩。噢，好吧。
"Signed, Nellie Goode."
“Nellie Goode签字”
Take off your hat, dear.
把帽子脱下，亲爱的。
There are simply millions
of things to do, I'm afraid.
恐怕，这里有很多事等着要做。
You won't mind if I depend
on you a great deal?
如果我对你非常依赖你不会介意吧？
Thank you, darling.
谢谢你，打令。
Now, get me out of these weeds.
I'm beginning to feel sad, and I shouldn't.
现在，替我把这些拿掉。
我开始觉得不开心，但我不能。
It's so depressing.
真让人伤心。
See who that is.
看看那是谁。
What's your name?
你叫什么名子？
Doris Tinsdale, madam.
Doris Tinsdale，夫人。
Yes? What is it, Groves?
是？什么事，Groves？
Divisional Detective Inspector Byard...
分区探长Byard…
...and Detective Inspector Smith
to see you, madam.
…和Smith探长要见你，夫人。
Good heavens.
我的天。
Hear that, Freddie? The police again.
你听到吗，Freddie？又是警察。
- Show them up, Groves.
- Very good, madam.
- 带他们进来，Grovers。
- 是的，夫人。
I thought I told you to wait downstairs.
我告诉你们在楼下等的。
Hand me a negligee from that cupboard
over there, will you, Phyllis?
在那衣柜里拿件外套给我，好吗，Phyllis？
Now, what about this dress for
the theatrical garden party, Miss Inwood?
现在，穿这裙子去戏院的园游会，
好吗InWood小姐？
Black? Oh, yes, of course.
黑色？噢，好，当然好。
How clever of you to remember, darling.
你真聪明还记得，打令。
Hold that for me, will you?
替我拿住，好吗？
- Freddie.
- Yes?
- Freddie。
- 什么？
We haven't decided. Am I going
to the theatrical garden party?
我们还没决定。我要不要去那剧院的园游会？
I don't feel an atom like it.
我不觉得我属于哪里。
I keep thinking about those
dreadful cancellations.
我不断的想起那取消演出。
I don't see why.
They're a compliment to you.
我看不出为什么。他们是你的恭维。
Hand me a comb and mirror
from over there, will you?
把梳子跟镜子那过来给我，好吗？
But they do cut down the takings.
但他们是取消了问话。
I think I could appear tonight,
if you insisted.
我像今晚我可以出现，如果你坚持的话。
Wouldn't it be a terrible strain for you?
那不是给你很大压力吗？
Oh, ghastly.
噢，真惊讶。
But I can't help feel
for my poor, dear, loyal public.
但我控制不了我那些，亲爱的，忠实的大众。
Looking towards it for weeks...
再等几周看看…
...and then trailing back sadly
with their tickets...
…然后用他们的戏票去回想这难过的情况…
...getting their money returned.
I simply can't bear it.
…用他们的钱来赔偿这一切。
我只是受不了。
It would be pretty trying.
这是值得尝试的。
Waves of sympathy coming on the stage...
同情的力量是来自舞台…
...all the gangways flooded with tears.
…每个观众都在哭。
I can hardly bear the thought myself.
我自己也忍不住要去想。
No use trying to stop me.
I'm going on tonight.
想停止我是没用的。我今晚会去。
Be at the theater at 6:00 sharp, will you?
你准时六点到剧院，好吗？
- Yes, madam.
- Take this away.
- 是，夫人。
- 走这边。
You go right ahead, dear.
Garden party dress and everything.
你太早了，亲爱的。
园游会的服装和其他的还没好。
And why don't we let ourselves
go a trifle just in front, huh?
那为什么不让我们先去办要事，嘿？
And thank you so very much.
那非常感谢你了。
What do you suppose
the police wants now?
你以为警察想要什么？
I don't know.
我不知道。
Must you speak to me
with your mouth full?
你一定要塞满嘴巴才跟我说话吗？
They've probably come to look under
your bed for Master Cooper.
他们可能会在你床底下去找Cooper先生。
What could I tell them about Cooper?
I know nothing about him.
我可以告诉他们Cooper什么？我对他一无所知。
Tell them just that.
就告诉他们这个。
Listen.
听着。
That's a good idea.
有个好提议。
Elsie, darling, come here.
Elsie，亲爱的，过来。
Now, I want you to wait
in the other room and listen.
现在，我想你去另一个房间等并留心听。
When you hear me cough, you come
in and say, "The doctor's here."
当你听到我咳嗽，你进来说，“医生来了。”
Yes, madam.
是，夫人。
You can stand just so much of detectives.
你对侦探的忍耐力真强。
After all, they are only policemen
with smaller feet.
说到底，他们只是警察里的小角色。
- In here?
- The next door, sir.
- 在这里？
- 另一道门，先生
What's the matter with Nellie?
Nellie有什么问题？
Oh, it's her stomach, sir,
if you'll excuse the expression.
噢，是她的胃，先生，如果没事我先告退。
The tragedy and excitement
was too much for her.
她经历的悲惨和刺激太多了。
- Highly strung type, eh?
- Oh, very, sir.
- 敏感脆弱型，嗯？
- 噢，是非常，先生。
I suppose you know, Miss Inwood,
that whatever Cooper's motive was...
我想你认识，Inwood小姐，
不管Cooper的动机为何…
...it certainly couldn't have been robbery.
…肯定不会是行劫。
Of course, darling. I understand that.
当然，亲爱的。这个我明白。
I suppose he just tried
to make it look like robbery.
我认为他只想造成像是行劫。
What's your name again?
再问一次你的名字是？
- Doris, sir.
- You know, Doris, you're not bad-looking.
- Doris，先生。
- 你知道吗，Doris，你不难看。
- Thank you, sir.
- You don't treat your face properly.
- 谢谢你，先生。
- 你没有好好打扮。
If you fixed your hair and used makeup,
you'd be quite attractive.
如果你弄一下头发和化点妆，你是挺有吸引力的。
I suppose I shouldn't have seen him
as often as I did.
我还以为我应该不会经常见到他。
But I didn't realize how madly
infatuated he was with me.
但我没有发现他对我是那么疯狂的着迷。
I just didn't realize.
我就是没有发现。
You'll never know how much
I blame myself for all this.
你永远不会知道为了这事有多么的责怪自己。
When my husband came back
from New York last week...
当我丈夫从上星期纽约回来…
...and I told Jonnie I couldn't see him...
…我告诉Jonnie我不能见他…
...he kept on phoning me.
…他不断打电话给我。
He wouldn't let me alone.
他不让我安静。
Oh, maybe if I had agreed to see him...
噢，或许我答应见他…
...he wouldn't have done
this dreadful thing.
…他不会做出这可怕的事。
- When did you last see Jonathan Cooper?
- Let me think.
- 你最后是什么时候见过Jonathan Cooper？
- 让我想想。
It must have been a week...
应该有一个礼拜…
A week before my husband died.
我丈夫去世前有一个礼拜。
- Go on. What are you waiting for?
- Did he come to this house?
- 继续。你在等什么？
- 他是来这房子吗？
Excuse me, madam.
The doctor's waiting to see you.
打扰一下，夫人。医生在等你。
Oh, I'm so sorry, darling,
but I will have to see my doctor.
噢，对不起，亲爱的，我要去见我的医生。
I'm feeling wretched.
I've been trying to get him all morning.
我觉得不舒服。我整个早上都在找他。
You see, I'm going on tonight.
你要明白，今晚我还要继续。
The producer has insisted so much.
那监制坚持要。
And I don't want to see him
ruined because of me.
我不想他因为我而搞砸。
That's all right. I think
we've covered most of the points.
没问题。我想我们已经差不多完了。
If there's any more I can help you with,
you will let me know?
如果还有其他可以帮助你们，请你告诉我？
Thank you. We'll try not
to trouble you again.
谢谢你。我们尽量不会再麻烦你。
Thank you.
谢谢。
You're so understanding.
你真明白事理。
And so are you.
你也是。
Doris, show the gentlemen out.
Doris，带这位先生出去。
It's all right, thank you. We can
find our own way downstairs.
不用了，谢谢你。我们知道怎样下楼。
Freddie.
Freddie。
Mavis, go to the kitchen
and get yourself some tea.
Mavis，你去厨房自己倒点茶喝吧。
- I'll ring when I need you.
- Yes. Thank you, madam.
- 需要你我会按铃。
- 是。谢谢你，夫人。
- Darling, where is Jonathan?
- Friends may be hiding him.
- 打令，Jonathan在那？
- 可能是朋友把他藏起来。
He had no friends, only me.
他没有朋友，除了我。
I hope he hasn't made any and hasn't
taken them into his confidence.
我希望他交不到朋友或是对他们没有信心。
For your sake, his sake and their sake.
为了你，为了他和他们都是好事。
- What do you mean?
- Lf the truth comes out, it would break you.
- 你是什么意思？
- 如果水落石出，你会受不了。
- I can't have that.
- What could you do?
- 我不能那样。
- 你可以怎样做？
You know me.
You know how it is with me.
你了解我。
你知道这会令我怎样。
- You make me afraid.
- Not I. You don't know what fear is.
- 你让我害怕。
- 不是我。你不知道什么是害怕。
Oh, that would be most lovely.
噢，这会是最好的。
Of course,
you must be fond of swimming.
当然，你一定很喜欢游泳。
But I am, yes I am,
very fond of it.
对，我是很喜欢，非常喜欢。
I go out to the country
to find somewhere to swim.
我到郊外去找个地方游泳。
You don't live in the country? Oh, dear.
你不是住在交区？噢，亲爱的。
Of course, we miss the rain so much, don't
we? All the flowers. It's so disappointing.
当然，我们很怀念下雨，不是吗？
各种鲜花。真是失望。
I really must apologize for Eve, Mr...?
Eve我真的要向你道歉，先生…？
- Was the name Smith?
- Smith, yes.
- 是叫Smith吗？
- 对，是Smith.
Smith.
The name seems familiar, somehow.
Smith。这名字有点熟，好像。
I can't understand
why that girl is so late.
我不明白为什么那女孩会那么迟。
I mean, she's usually so punctual.
我是说，她平时很准时的。
She takes that from me.
Her father isn't punctual.
她跟我学的。她爸爸也不守时。
He catches trains and things,
but always at the last moment.
他会赶上火车和其他事，但总是在最后一刻。
I'm there at least an hour before.
我会提前一小时到。
Yes. I'm sure you are.
I have heard a lot about you, Mrs. Gill.
是，我肯定你是。
我听过很多关于你的事，Gill小姐
Oh, have you? Is Eve very fond of me?
噢，你有吗？Eve是不是很喜欢我？
Have you known her long, Mr. Smith?
I've got the name right now, haven't I?
你认识她很久吗，Smith先生？
我刚刚才知道这名字，不是吗？
I've known her
for about a day and a half.
我认识她差不多有一天半。
That's not very long.
那不算久。
Where did you meet?
在哪里认识的？
As a matter of fact,
we met in the saloon bar of a pub.
事实上，我们是在酒吧里认识的。
Well.
这样。
How interesting.
挺有趣的。
Thank you.
谢谢。
- Am I intruding?
- This is Mr. Smith.
- 我有打扰吗？
- 这是Smith先生。
Mr. Smith, this is Eve's father.
We see him now and again.
Smith先生，这是Eve的父亲。
我们不会常常见到他。
- How do you do, sir?
- Very well, indeed. Thank you.
- 你好吗，先生？
- 很好。谢谢。
- Do sit down.
- Thank you.
- 请坐下。
- 谢谢。
- Where's Eve?
- She should be here by this time.
- Eve在哪里？
- 她应该马上就到。
She asked Mr. Smith to tea.
她约了Smith先生喝茶。
Oh, good, good.
Anyone else coming?
噢，好，好。还有谁会来吗？
I mean, going to be a party?
I am fond of parties.
我是说，会有个派对吗？我喜欢派对。
No. There's no one else coming,
and you weren't invited.
不。没有其他人来的，你也没有被邀请。
Wasn't I? Oh, an oversight.
不会吧？噢，太大意了。
But I forgive you.
但我原谅你。
Forgiveness, Mr. Smith.
The secret of a happy married life.
原谅，Smith先生。是快乐婚姻的秘密。
That and good long stretches of the
absence that makes the heart grow fonder.
加上长期分开会增加爱意。
There you are, my dear.
The last but four of the Mahicans.
这就对了，亲爱的。四个Mahicans里的最后一个。
- Will you forgive me, Mr. Ordinary Smith?
- Yes. I've just been set an example.
- 你会原谅我吗，OrdinarySmith先生？
- 会。我刚举成为一个例子。
Yes, but he says his name
is just plain Smith.
是，但他只说他叫Smith。
He did? I'm terribly sorry to be late...
他有吗？真对不起我迟到了…
...but the rehearsal went on and
the awful part is, I have to go back.
…但彩排继续最坏的是，我要回去。
- It was decent of you to have come.
- What are you doing here?
- 你能来已经是挺有心了。
- 你在这干嘛？
- I've been trying to reach you all day.
- I took the boat out.
- 我整天在找你。
- 我开船出海了。
We had quite a little cruise.
我们游历了不少地方。
Jonnie and me.
Jonnie和我。
Poor old Jonnie.
I hope his rheumatism is better.
可怜的Jonnie。希望他的关节炎好点。
Do play something, Mr. Smith.
Mr. Smith is a pianist, Mother.
来弹奏一下吧，Smith先生。
Smith先生是个钢琴师，妈妈。
Well, I think that's a delightful career.
嗯，我想这是很受欢迎的职业。
- I often wish I'd kept up my practicing.
- It's not exactly my career, Mrs. Gill.
- 我常常希望我有坚持我的练习。
- 这不算是我的职业，Gill先生。
But you must play for us.
Make him, Mother.
但你一定要为我们演奏。说服他，妈妈。
But I haven't even started my tea yet.
但我连茶都没喝过。
But of course he hasn't.
Eve, you are ridiculous.
这是当然的。Eve，你太过分了。
But I've got to leave in a minute.
Please play.
但我很快就要走。请你演奏嘛。
You know, Jonnie's not
much of a sailor, Eve.
你知道吗，Jonnie不是水手，Eve。
He was abominably seasick.
他晕船晕得很厉害。
In fact, as soon as we got ashore,
Jonnie ran away.
实际上，我们一到岸，Jonnie就走了。
- Who's Jonnie?
- I wish I knew.
- Jonnie是谁？
- 我希望我知道。
He's about 57 different varieties.
他大概有57个品种。
Roughly speaking, he was a dog of some
sort that strayed in a couple of nights ago.
简单的说，他是几天前跟我同行的一支狗。
- Do the police know about him?
- No, no. I'm not worried about him.
- 是不是警察知道他什么？
- 不，不。我不担心他。
I daresay he'll find his way
back to his old master.
我敢说他会找到他的主人。
Or mistress.
或是女主人。
I thought we might have to ask
for your help, Mr. Smith.
我还以为我们需要你帮忙，Smith先生。
Mr. Smith is a detective, Mother.
Simth先生是个侦探，妈妈。
Mrs. Mason.
Mason太太。
A detective. How very unusual.
一个侦探。真不寻常。
I suppose you have
many fascinating cases.
我想你有很多非常有趣的案件。
- Must be very exciting.
- Not very, I'm afraid.
- 一定是很刺激。
- 恐怕不是。
- Embezzlement, fraud, petty thefts.
- Smuggling?
- 亏空公款，诈骗，盗窃。
- 走私？
Yes. Occasionally. Brandy mostly.
是。偶尔。大多数是白兰地。
Murder, too, sometimes, Father.
有时候，还有，谋杀，爸爸。
Mr. Smith is working on the Inwood case.
Smith先生在查Inwood的案件。
Oh, you don't say so.
Yes, I read about that somewhere.
噢，你没有说。是，我在某地方看到的。
How did you know?
你怎样知道？
I saw your photograph in the paper.
我在报纸上看过你的照片。
What is the fellow's name, Clippen.
你人的名字叫什么，Clippen。
Cooper, Cooper.
Did he do it, do you think?
Cooper，Cooper。
你认为，是他干的吗？
He has run away and remained in hiding.
他跑了一直躲起来。
We're inclined to accept the obvious
as being obvious.
我们倾向接受明显的。
Oh, it's just like Sherlock Holmes
and his fiddle.
噢，就好像福尔摩斯和他的把戏。
A stream of beautiful sound,
and then suddenly out pops the solution.
一轮美妙的声音，然后突然冒出答案。
- Oh, I must run.
- So must I.
- 噢，我赶时间。
- 我要走了。
- I don't know what you'll think of me.
- I like people bound up in their work.
- 我不知道你会怎样想我。
- 我喜欢投入工作的人。
- You'll make a very good actress indeed.
- Au revoir, my pet.
- 你将会是个很好的女演员。
- Au revoir，我的宠物。
Meet me at the stage door...
在后台的门口等我…
- Can't I drive you back to the Academy?
- No. I want you to get to know Father.
- 我不可以送你回学院吗？
- 不。我想你多认识爸爸。
Not professionally,
but he's a wonderful character.
不是工作上，但他是个很好的人物。
- They'd be hurt if you didn't stay.
- When will I see you again?
- 如果你不留下他们会不开心。
- 我什么时候可以再见你？
- Well, I really don't...
- Ring me tomorrow first thing. Regent 1113.
- 嗯，我真的不知…
- 明天一早打电话给我。丽晶1113。
I know you think I'm an idiot,
but I'm not. I'm doing darn well.
我知道你认为我是笨蛋，但我不是。
我做得挺好的。
Yes. You're giving a very good show.
A very good show.
是。你的演出非常好。非常好。
- Pity you've no audience.
- But you're my audience.
- 可惜你没有观众。
- 你就是我的观众。
I wish you'd give me a little
applause now and then.
我一直都希望你给我一点掌声。
- I wonder when Jonathan will turn up.
- Turn up where?
- 我很好奇Jonathan什么时候会出现。
- 哪里出现？
Wherever Miss Charlotte Inwood
happens to be.
在Charlotte Inwood小姐出现的地方。
Good heavens, she'll only turn him over.
天呀，她只会举报他。
Yes, and to your nice new friend,
Mr. Smith.
是，找给你那不错的新朋友，Smith先生。
Who was that man?
那人是谁？
Oh, that was my dad, madam.
噢，他是我爸，夫人。
I told him about my temporary job,
and he doesn't like it.
我告诉他我的临时工作，他不喜欢。
What with the murder and all.
You know, madam.
关于谋杀和其他的。你也明白，夫人。
What's it got to do with him?
Or with you?
这跟他有什么关系？还有你？
My dad says that man on the run
might turn up here.
我爸说那逃走的男人可能在这出现。
Might even get into the dressing room.
也可能会跑进更衣室。
Might even murder me, madam.
还可能会把我也杀了，夫人。
It's the scene of the crime the murderer
returns to, not the theater.
谋杀犯会回到案发现场，不是剧院。
He might be right, my dad.
我爸，他可会能猜对。
I'm surprised you're not
a bit afraid yourself.
我很惊讶你自己一点都不害怕。
Slippers.
拖鞋。
This theater's the last place
he'd want to be seen in.
这戏院是他最不可能出现的地方。
Now, stop acting like a silly schoolgirl.
现在，不要再像个傻傻的女学生。
The only murderer here
is the orchestra leader.
这里唯一的杀人犯就是那乐队领班。
Father, you've got to keep on the lookout
and head Jonathan off.
爸爸，你要继续小心点还有提点Jonathan。
Right. Certainly, my dear.
好。一定，亲爱的。
This is desperate.
真是有点绝望。
Go on, go on, go on.
继续，继续，继续。
Madam, madam.
夫人，夫人。
- What?
- Madam, there's a man.
- 什么事？
- 夫人，有个男人。
- He's gone up to your dressing room.
- What are you talking about? What man?
- 他走到你的更衣室。
- 你说什么？什么男人？
I saw him. Don't go up there.
It's dangerous.
我看见他。不要上去。有危险。
You're an imbecile.
你真是个傻瓜。
You needn't come up.
你不用上来。
I'll manage to change myself.
我自己换衣服就好了。
I know, Jonnie, darling,
but what a terrible risk you've taken.
我知道，Jonnie，打令，但你冒很大风险。
- I couldn't keep away.
- You haven't told me where you've been.
- 我不能一直躲开。
- 你还没告诉我你去了哪里。
Some friends looked after me.
有些朋友在照顾我。
- What friends?
- Never mind that just now.
- 什么朋友？
- 现在不用管这些。
We've got to work out
a plan of campaign.
我们要想办法解决这情况。
- Everything is going on beautifully.
- We've got to get a story...
- 所以事也是向好方面发展。
- 我们要编个故事…
...and we'll both have to stick to it.
- I must change.
…我们的口供要一致。
- 我要换衣服。
You shouldn't have come here, Jonnie.
You have been so wonderful up to now.
你不应该来这里，Jonnie。
你一直都做得很好直到现在。
Don't think that I'm ungrateful.
I'm not. Truly, I'm not.
不要以为我不感激你。我不是。真的，我不是。
- I don't know how I shall ever repay you.
- Repay me?
- 我不知道我可以怎样回报你。
- 回报我？
You talk as though this were a favor.
你说成好像这是种帮忙。
Something that a "thank you"
can take care of.
是些说句“谢谢”就可以解决的。
Dearest, you mustn't be foolish.
You must go away at once. Back to...
亲爱的，你不要太傻。你一定要马上走。回到…
...where you were hiding.
…你躲起来的地方。
Freddie's going to get you
out of the country soon.
Freddie很快会把你送到国外。
And I'll come to see you,
when the run of the show's over.
当这次演出的期满，我会去看你。
Why, that may be months,
maybe a year, or more.
为什么，将要几个月，可能是一年，或更长。
Well, you know how it is. We were
playing to capacity before this happened.
唔，你也知道是怎样。
在这件事之前我们也要做完演期。
Now they're hanging on to the chandeliers.
现在他们要挂起那吊灯。
Fifty pounds up tonight.
有五十磅就在今晚。
Goodness knows how they squeeze them in.
天晓得他们怎样挤进出。
Yes. I could only get standing room.
对。我只能有站的位置。
Well, there you are.
嗯，你在哪里。
We'll find a lovely place,
South America or somewhere.
我们可以找个美丽的地方，南美或是其他地方。
And I'll come out to you, as soon
as all of this has blown over.
等到这事情转淡后我会去你哪里。
I'll be glad of the rest for a week or two.
我会很高兴去休息一两个礼拜。
Palm trees...
棕榈树…
...sunshine.
…阳光。
Lovely.
好美。
A week or two?
一两个礼拜？
Well, you don't want me to give up
everything, do you?
唔，你不想我放弃一切吧，是不是？
Why not? I have.
为什么不？我已经放弃一切。
Now, Jonnie, I thought you said that
my happiness was all that mattered...
现在，Jonnie，你说过我的快乐是最重要…
...and you must admit that
you behaved as if it was.
…你要承认你以前是这样认为。
Taking all the trouble
to protect my reputation...
承担所有麻烦去保护我的声誉…
...covering up the accident...
…隐瞒这意外…
...destroying that dreadful dress
with the bloodstain on it.
…毁灭那有血迹的裙子。
I didn't destroy it.
我没有毁灭它。
You didn't?
你没有？
Jonnie, you promised.
Jonnie，你答应我的。
Don't you realize if they find the dress...
你不知道如果他们找到那裙子…
So long as I have that dress, I'm the one
who decides how long this show will run.
只要我有这裙子，这场戏要演多久由我决定。
And everything else.
还有其他的事。
Do you understand?
你明白吗？
Where the devil is Miss Inwood?
The orchestra's started her number.
Inwood小姐究竟在哪里？乐队已经开始她那段。
My socks and suspenders, where is she?
我的袜子和袜带，她在哪里？
Take this. I'll change downstairs.
那这个。我会在楼下换衣服。
Sorry, darling. A hook broke.
对不起，亲爱的。有个钩子断了。
Just a minute, Charlie.
Jonathan Cooper's in the theater.
等一下，Charlie。Jonathan Cooper在剧院。
The sergeant's seen him.
He was sure to make for your room.
警长看见他。他肯定去了你的房间。
- Have you seen him?
- Of course not. What a stupid idea.
- 你有见到他吗？
- 当然没有。真是荒谬。
I think I better take a look
at your dressing room.
我想最好让我看看你的更衣室。
Doris, show Sergeant Loomis where to go.
Doris，带Loomis警长去吧。
- Freddie, there's something...
- Miss Inwood, please.
- Freddie，哪里有些…
- Inwood小姐，请。
Doris, what are you waiting for?
Doris，你在等什么？
Oh, Mr. Loomis, I feel so queer.
It's my heart.
噢，Loomis先生，我觉得很奇怪。是我的心。
The doctor told me I should
take the stairs easy.
医生叫我走楼梯要慢些。
You don't think he'll try to shoot
his way out, do you?
你想他不会开枪杀出去吧，是不是？
He might be desperate, sergeant.
他可能绝望，警长。
Don't you think you ought
to go back and get a policeman?
你不觉得你应该回去带个警察来吗？
She was glad he got away, Father.
她巴不得他离开，爸爸。
- How do you know?
- By a look she gave Freddie Williams.
- 你怎么知道？
- 凭她看Freddie Williams的眼神。
"Look she gave"? That won't get you far.
“她的眼神”？你跑不了多远。
She'd be more delighted if she knew
there was no stained dress.
她会更高兴如果她知道那裙子已经不存在。
Oh, yes.
噢，是呀。
- I wish we still had that dress.
- There's so very little time.
- 我希望我们还有那裙子。
- 已经没有时间了。
We've got to make every minute count.
我们要争取每分每秒。
I have to phone Smith tomorrow.
我明天要打电话给Smith。
Why don't I invite him to the theatrical
garden party with me?
我什么不邀请他陪我去剧院的园游会？
I have to sell programs there.
我要在那里推销节目。
- I don't quite follow you, my dear Holmes.
- In order to make him see.
- 我不是很明白你，我亲爱的Holmes。
- 要让他看见。
Nobody suspects our Charlotte yet,
and they've got to.
还没有人怀疑我们的Charlotte，
一定要让他们怀疑。
First, you'd see my mother and father
and get approved by them.
首先，你要见我父亲和母亲让他们同意。
Most parents nowadays don't seem
to care what sort of people...
现在大多数父母好像不在乎是什么人…
...their children go around with,
but I'm not like that.
…跟他们的孩子来往，但我不是。
I know I'm very old-fashioned,
but I've got to think of Eve.
我知道我是守旧，但我要为Eve设想。
What do you do for a living?
你是做什么的？
I write a bit.
我有写点东西。
What, novels and things?
什么，小说和其他？
I'm very fond of novels. You know,
I read a delightful one the other day.
我很喜欢小说。你知道吗，
我前一阵子看过一本很好的。
Let me see. What was the title?
It was written by that woman.
让我想想。书名是什么？是个女作家写的。
I can't remember, but she's written
a number of books.
我想不起来，但她写过好几本书。
You must have read some of them.
They're all about charming people.
你肯定看过一些。它们都是关于些漂亮的人。
She only writes
about the nice side of life.
她只写人生美好的一面。
Now, this book I was telling you about...
我现在告诉你的这本书是关于…
...the title has just slipped
my memory for the moment.
…书名刚闪过我的记忆。
Well, it's about a mother, which is
a nice idea, I think, don't you?
唔，它是写一个母亲，我让为是个不错的点子，
你说呢？
One reads so much
about the younger generation.
当一个人看那么多关于年青一代的。
It does seem a brilliant idea
to have a change.
改变一下真是个非常好的提议。
Now, this mother isn't old...
那母亲年纪不是很大…
I'm sorry to turn up so late,
but I'm stranded for the night.
对不起我那么迟才到，我昨晚被延误了。
All the hotels are full.
My flat's uninhabitable.
所有酒店都满了。我的公寓不能住。
I told you, it's in the hands
of the decorators.
我告诉过你，它正在装修。
I know it's a frightful imposition...
我知道是非常不适当…
...but I wondered if you could
give me a shakedown somewhere?
…但可否给我安排个地方？
Well, of course we can.
这个，当然可以。
Can't we, Mother?
行吗，妈妈？
Well, it's a little awkward.
可是，这有点困难。
Is your father proposing
to stay here too?
你爸爸也打算留下来吗？
Well, Jonathan could have my room,
and I could sleep on the settee.
那么，Jonathan可以住我的房间，我睡沙发。
Where shall we put your father?
我们把你爸爸安排在那？
No. I'll sleep on the settee,
and you can sleep with your mama.
不。我睡沙发，你可以跟你妈妈睡。
- I hate to put you to all this trouble.
- Not at all, Mr...? What is your name?
- 我讨厌给你那么多麻烦。
- 不会，…先生？你叫什么名字？
- Jones.
- Brown.
- Jones。
- Brown。
Robinson. Now, Mr. Robinson,
I think we'll make it bye-byes.
Robinson。这样，Robinson先生，
我想我们要说再见了。
A blanket for the commodore,
and we'll all go to bye-byes.
给指挥官一张毛毯，我们都要说再见了。
Robinson. I've heard that name before.
Robinson。我以前听过这名字。
No, it won't do. Has Eve gone mad,
turning the house into a hotel in the night?
不，这不行。Eve是不是疯了，
这晚把房子变成酒店？
Who is this man, anyway?
What is his name?
说回来，那男人是谁？他叫什么名字？
Well, perhaps you better not mention it.
这样，你还是不要说比较好。
The fact is that he's
a fugitive from justice.
事实上他是个逃犯。
The whole police force is on his heels,
and Eve...
所有警察都在追捕他，Eve…
Well, for reasons of her own, my dear,
doesn't want him to be caught.
唔，亲爱的，她有自己的原因，不想他被捕。
He's...
他是…
He's wanted for murder.
他是谋杀嫌疑犯。
Now you're going too far.
现在你太过分了。
I suppose you think I believed that
that Mr. Smith, who came here to tea...
我假设你认为我相信Smith先生，是来喝茶…
...was a real detective.
…是个真的侦探。
If I hadn't heard her maid's voice outside
the dressing room, they'd have got me.
如果我没有听到她佣人在更衣室外的声音，
他们早就把我抓了。
Eve, darling, I know I should
never have trusted her.
Eve，亲爱的，我知道我不该相信她。
Darling, you've been wonderful to me.
I don't deserve it, but I need you.
打令，你一直对我很好。我不值，但我需要你。
I need you more than ever.
我比以前更需要你。
Tonight, when I found
what Charlotte was...
今晚，当我发现Charlotte是…
...all of a sudden,
I thought my brain would burst.
…突然，我的头好像要爆开。
After all that I'd done for her.
我为她所做的一切。
Everything I did for her was because
I loved her and she loved me.
我为她所做的一切是因为我爱她她也爱我。
- I'm so sorry.
- Why the umbrella?
- 真对不起。
- 为什么带伞？
It is a garden party, isn't it?
这是个园游会，不是吗？
Oh, Roehampton Club, please.
噢，麻烦你，去Roehampton会所。
It couldn't be helped, I'm afraid.
You must blame a Miss Doris Tinsdale.
我恐怕，这帮不上忙。
你要怪Doris Tinsdale小姐。
Who is Doris Tinsdale?
谁是Doris Tinsdale？
She's Charlotte Inwood's temporary dresser.
We've been searching for her all afternoon.
她是Charlotte Inwood的临时佣人。
我们整个下午也在找她。
One of our men at the theater...
我们在剧院的人…
...let her slip through his fingers
without making a statement.
…还没有问口供就让她走了。
You look very lovely.
你很可爱。
You're very sweet to say so.
你真会说话。
What has this Doris Tinsdale person
got to do with the case?
这个Doris Tinsdale的人跟这案件有什么关系？
Or shouldn't I ask, Mr. Smith?
或许我应该问，Smith先生？
Well, Cooper was at the theater last night,
and we think she saw him.
唔，Cooper昨晚在剧院出现，我们认为她看见他。
And don't call me Mr. Smith.
After all, my name is...
还有不要叫我Smith先生。我名字叫…
Wilfred.
Wilfred。
Not very good, is it?
不是很好，是吗？
It suits some people very nicely.
跟某些人非常搭配。
I rather liked it when you called me
"Ordinary Smith."
我情愿你叫我“普通人Smith”。
- Oh, I didn't mean to, really.
- But I liked it. I liked it very much.
- 噢，我不是故意的，真的。
- 但我喜欢。我很喜欢。
Please go on calling me that, will you?
请继续这样叫我，好吗？
Yes, I will.
好，我会。
What were we talking about?
我们在说什么？
Oh, yes. I was going to ask you,
why did Cooper risk going to the theater?
噢，对。我本来要问你，
为什么Cooper要冒险到剧院？
He must have had a very strong reason
for wanting to talk to Miss Inwood.
他一定有很重要的原因要跟Inwood小姐说话。
- Let's not talk shop on a day like this.
- Oh, I am sorry.
- 我们不要整天都谈这些。
- 噢，对不起。
Do you hate inquisitive people?
你不喜欢追根究底的人？
Of course not. I'm one myself.
当然不会。我自己也是。
But seriously, Ordinary, do you think there's
anything between Cooper and Miss Inwood?
但认真的，按常理的，你认为Cooper
和Inwood小姐之间是不是有些什么？
Seriously, "Extraordinary,"
I shouldn't be a bit surprised.
认真的，“不寻常的，”我一点也不觉得惊讶。
What a curious person she must be.
她肯定是一个非常好奇的人。
I mean, going back on the stage
so soon after everything.
我是说，发生那么多事可以马上回到舞台。
The show must go on.
表演一定要继续。
A smiling face, a breaking heart.
Actors rather like it, I'm told.
一张笑脸，一颗破碎的心。有人说，演员最喜欢。
But today...
但今天…
...going right from the funeral
to the garden party.
…从丧礼直接到园游会。
I must say, I think that's
overdoing things a bit.
我只可以说，我觉得有点过火。
A strong sense of the dramatics
and all that sort of thing.
所有的一切加起来太过戏剧性了。
It's...
她是…
...so cold and calculating of her.
…太冷淡和太算计了。
Is it?
是吗？
Yes, it is.
是，没错。
If she's that cold and calculating,
I was wondering...
如果她是那么冷漠和算计，我怀疑…
...maybe she had something to do
with her husband's death.
…她可能和她丈夫的死有关。
Were you?
你觉得是？
After all...
这一切…
...there must be a lot
that doesn't appear on the surface.
…肯定有很多事情不是那么表面。
I mean, like...
我的意思是，好像…
...wheels within wheels.
…轮子里面还有轮子。
Who...? Who knows what goes on
in a woman's mind?
谁…？谁知道女人在想什么？
I don't know.
我不知道。
And if I don't know, I...
如果我不知道，我…
Well...
那么…
...who?
…是谁？
A woman's mind sometimes...
女人的想法有时候…
I was saying that a woman's mind...
我是说女人的想法…
That's right.
没错。
Do you really?
你真的认为？
I think so too.
我也是这么想。
In Miss Inwood's case?
在Inwood小姐的案子？
What?
什么？
I have to report to the committee tent
to get my programs.
我要到委员帐幕去报到取我的节目。
- Whether to give it to the orphans
or to let the government take it.
- 去给那些孤儿们
或是让政府拿走。
I'm putting it to you!
我让你决定吧！
There's the committee tent over there.
委员帐幕就在哪里。
You do understand I won't be able to spend
the whole afternoon with you?
我不能整个下午陪你你明白吗？
Can't I go with you? I can sell a mean
program. We bloodhounds have methods.
我不能跟你一起去吗？我可以卖些节目。
我们这些猎狗自有办法。
But you must go and amuse yourself.
I can't take you with me.
但你需要自己去找些娱乐。我不能带上你。
Every time I begin to think I know
what color your eyes are, you disappear.
每次我开始看清楚你眼睛的颜色，你就消失了。
But it's against the rules. Now please go.
I'll pick you up later. I'll get in trouble.
但这是违反规则的。请你走吧。
我等一下会去接你。我会有麻烦。
Right here. Step right up.
Yes, madam. Over here...
在这里。上来吧。
是，夫人。在这里…
Eve, you brute. Wherever have you been?
You're hours late.
Eve，你这怪物。你去了哪里？你迟了几个小时。
- I'm sorry, Chubby.
- What a day. What a day.
- 对不起，Chubby。
- 难熬的一天。难熬的一天。
- Hello, Valerie.
- Hello, Eve.
- 你好，Valerie.
- 你好，Eve。
Oh, this is Wilfred Smith.
Chubby Bannister and Valerie Maynard.
噢，这位是Wilfred Smith。
Chubby Bannister和Valerie Maynard。
They're at RADA with me.
他们是跟我一起在皇家戏剧学院的。
- Well, how do you do, Mr. Smith?
- How do you do?
- 唔，你好吗，Smith先生？
- 你好吗？
I'm sure you'd love some ice cream.
Chubby could show you where it is.
我想你一定喜欢雪糕。Chubby可以带你去拿。
- Oh, but I'd adore to.
- That's most good of you.
- 噢，我非常乐意。
- 你真好。
I hope you'll remember me by this little
token of my regard and esteem.
我希望你因为这一点好处和优点记住我。
Allow me.
请让我。
As you know, this fete is being held
for the aid of the Actors' Orphanage.
你也知道，这派对是为了
演员孤儿院而开的。
Now, it's raining outside, and if you've
got half a pound to spare, come in...
现在，外面在下雨，如果你有
多余的半英镑花，进来…
Which programs shall I take?
我应该拿那些节目表？
- Take that pile, dear.
- Thank you.
- 柱子吧，亲爱的。
- 谢谢。
You newspaperwomen work hard
at your job, don't you, Miss Gill?
你们女记者很勤快，是吗，Gill小姐？
How did you know my name?
你怎么知道我的名字？
Called that number you gave me
for emergency.
打你给我那遇到意外的电话号码。
A Mrs. Gill answered,
and I put two and two together.
一个Gill太太给的答案，我就慢慢猜出来了。
- What did you need me for in such a hurry?
- Don't talk to me like that.
- 你这么急找我想我怎样？
- 不要用这种语气跟我说话。
I've come down here to tell you
Miss Inwood's looking for you.
我来告诉你Inwood小姐在找你。
- What does she want?
- She wants your head, of course.
- 她想要什么？
- 她当然想要你的头。
What's more, she said the police want
to talk to a Miss Doris Tinsdale.
还有，她说警察想跟Doris Tinsdale小姐谈谈。
She wants to know when I'm going
back to my work.
她想知道我什么时候回去工作。
I told her my stomach
was still out of order.
我告诉她我的胃还没有好。
Well, it's better now.
唔，现在好点了。
- Much better, thank you.
- You want more money, don't you?
- 好很多，谢谢你。
- 你想要多些钱，不是吗？
Well, look at the risk I'm running. I'd better
go to Miss Inwood and tell her everything.
嗯，你看我现在所冒的险。
我还是把一切告诉Inwood小姐比较好。
And before that detective finds out
there's no such person as Doris.
在那警探发现没有Doris这人以前。
Here's 5 pounds. It's all I have with me.
这里是五英镑。是我的全部。
Oh, my job's worth more than that,
at least another 20.
噢，我的工作不只这个数，最少再来二十。
I'll meet you outside Miss Inwood's tent
in half an hour.
我们半小时后在Inwood的帐幕外见面。
Finished already? You are doing well.
好了没有？你做的不错。
- May I use your phone?
- Why, yes, of course, my dear. There it is.
- 我可以用电话吗？
- 为什么,当然可以，亲爱的。在哪里。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Hello. Is that you, Father?
你好。是你吗，爸爸？
Could you come right away? With all
the money you can lay your hands on.
你现在可以过来吗？把你身上所有钱都拿来。
At least 20 pounds. At least!
最少二十英镑。最少！
It's Nellie.
是Nellie。
The girl I'm understudying.
那个我低估的女人。
Yes. Be quick, darling.
是。快点，打令。
No queuing.
不用排队。
No queuing here.
Step right up.
不用在这排队。
直接上来。
Yes, madam, over here...
是，夫人，到这里来…
Doris, isn't it?
是不是Doris？
Yes, sir.
是，先生。
Yes, sir. I took your advice, sir.
I done myself up.
是，长官。我接受你的忠告，长官。我自首。
I mean, what do you think of it?
我意思是，你怎样想？
- Where have you been?
- Oh, I can explain it, sir.
- 你去了哪里？
- 噢，我可以解析，长官。
- Only yesterday...
- Come along. I'll take you to Miss Inwood.
- 只是昨天…
- 来吧。我带你去Inwood小姐哪里。
Come on, hurry.
来吧，快点。
Roll up, roll up, roll up. Come and have
a good time. Come on, sir. You, sir...
过来，过来，过来。来这里
享受一下。来吧，先生。你，先生…
Miss Tinsdale to see you.
Tinsdale小姐来见你。
Well, this is a pleasure. Where have
you been? I thought you were dead.
这样，真是幸会。你去了哪里？我还以为你死了。
Oh, no, madam. I wasn't.
As a matter of fact...
噢，不，夫人。我没有。事实上…
You needn't go into detail. I hope you're not
turning into one of those explicit people...
你不需要太清楚。我希望你不会变成那种…
...who always tell you exactly
how they feel when you ask them.
…只在你问的时候才告诉你他们的感受的人。
You did leave me a trifle suspended,
however.
但你只留给我些无关痛痒的。
I'm sorry, madam.
对不起，夫人。
I was held up.
我被留住了。
Darling!
打令！
Whatever happened to that
peculiar figure of yours?
你那骄人的身材怎么了？
It's a new dress, madam.
这是条新裙子，夫人。
Keep it, dear.
留着吧，亲爱的。
What it does for you is worth thousands.
它对你来说值好几千。
I bought it at a sale.
我在减价的时候买的。
Don't confide in me.
Just pour some tea, would you?
别告诉我秘密。倒点茶，好吗？
By the way, Doris...
说回来，Doris…
...did Nellie tell you the police
want to talk to you?
…有没有告诉你警察想找你问话？
But whatever for, madam?
但关于什么，夫人？
Oh, I hope they won't upset my dad.
噢，希望他们没让我爸担心。
- My dad said...
- They're not going to eat you, darling.
- 我爸说…
- 他们不会把你吃掉，亲爱的。
It's not important. Just pull yourself
together and pour the tea.
这不重要。只要保持冷静来倒茶。
Rehearsals from morning till night.
If we wanted to misbehave...
从早到晚的彩排。如果我们想捣蛋…
...we couldn't find a minute to do it in.
- No.
…我们还有时间。
- 不。
Yes, so I understand. Eve tells me she kept
hard at it all day and evening.
好，我明白了。
Eve告诉我她从白天到晚上都在努力。
But Eve hasn't been near for days. I thought
she was home with a cold or something.
但Eve离开了几天。我以为她不舒服在家。
- Maybe she's got a job in a show.
- Gosh.
- 可能她在演出中找到工作。
- Gosh。
A fortune in five minutes,
and there's no income tax on it tonight.
五分钟的发财机会，
还不用缴入息税就在今晚。
Excuse me, madam. I've...
对不起，夫人。我…
I've got to sneeze.
我要打喷嚏。
- Miss Livingston, I presume.
- That's not my name.
- 我想你是，Livingston小姐。
- 那不是我的名字。
Oh, no, no. It's Nellie Goode, isn't it?
But what does the name matter?
不，不，不。这是Nellie Goode，不是吗？
但这个名字有什么关系？
After all, I could think of lots of much
more appropriate names for you.
其实，我可以想出一大堆更适合你的名字。
Yes, I could think of a few for you too.
Who are you?
对，我也可以想出几个给你。你是谁？
I understand my daughter has entered
into a somewhat shady transaction.
我明白我女儿在走霉运。
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- Well, you are a blackmailer, aren't you?
- 我不知道你在说什么。
- 嗯，你想勒索，是不是？
You know, that's a very,
very naughty thing to be.
你要知道，那是非常，非常丑恶的事。
Don't say things like that to me.
You could be had up for a thing like that.
不要把我说成这样。
你可能会做出这种事。
Now, don't be so peppery.
现在，不要太刻薄。
- I like to keep things on a friendly basis.
- One short.
- 我喜欢用友善的方式去处理事情。
- 小了一张。
It's all I've got. You don't want
me to walk home...
这是我的全部。你不想我走路回去…
I don't care if you crawl home.
我才不管你是否爬回家。
Oh, well, it doesn't matter. I'm not mean.
And you've got till tomorrow morning.
噢，那，没所谓。我不会计较。你明早再给也可以。
Father, Freddie Williams, Charlotte's
manager, spotted me as Doris.
父亲，Freddie Williams，Charlotte的经理人,
认得我是Doris。
I had to go into Charlotte's tent.
我一定要进去Charlotte的帐幕。
If there's one thing I hate,
it's saying I told you so.
如果有件我讨厌的事，就是说我告诉过你。
And the police want to talk to Doris.
I don't know which way to turn.
而警察想跟Doris谈话。
我不知道转那一边。
I think I'll get Smith
and tell him the whole story.
我想我会找Smith告诉他一切。
Have you got him to suspect
Charlotte yet?
你让他怀疑Charlotte没有？
I'm afraid not.
恐怕没有。
But I thought you had to pick him up at
Whitehall. Didn't you talk to him about it?
但我以为你在Whitehall接他。你没有跟他说过？
But, yes, I did...
可是，有，我有说…
...in a way.
…在路上。
In a way?
在路上？
Oh, I see.
噢，我明白了。
Some more important topic arose
in the conversation.
有些更重要的话题。
Only there's one slight complication,
my dear: Jonathan.
现在只剩下一点小麻烦，我亲爱的：Jonathan。
You're not, by any chance, thinking
of changing horses in midstream?
你不会，想在中途换马？
Father, is it awful of me?
爸爸，我是不是很坏？
Not awful, my dear,
just rather a bad bit of timing.
不是坏，亲爱的，只是时机不对。
No matter how my feelings
toward him change...
不管我对他的感觉怎样改变…
...I still can't let Jonathan down, can I?
…我也不能让Jonathan失望，不是吗？
Not while he's hiding in our house.
不能在他还躲在我们房子的时候。
Call yourself an actress? There's your
big scene, if you have the pluck to take it.
还说你自己是演员？
这是你的大舞台，如果你有胆量去演。
You have the law on your arm. All you have
to do is rush in there and shout, "Stop!
法律就在你手上。你只需要跑进去大声说，“停！
That woman is a murderess!"
那女人就是凶手！”
And then she'll say, "How dare you?"
And you'll say, "I'll dare and dare again.
接着她会说，“你怎能这样？”
你会说，“我会继续这样。
What about the bloodstained dress,
eh, Miss Charlotte Inwood?"
那有血迹的裙子怎样，
嗯，Charlotte Inwood小姐”。
- And then she'll say...
- Please. This is serious, Father.
- 然后她说…
- 拜托。这很严重，爸爸。
- Oh, Eve! There you are.
- I couldn't find you anywhere.
- 噢，Eve！你在这里。
- 我到处也找不到你。
- I've been trying to get rid of my programs.
- I've been too busy talking to sell mine.
- 我一直在摆脱我的节目。
- 我一直不停的说话去推销我的。
Do you think I talk too much?
你觉得我是否说得太多？
No. Most women don't talk enough.
不。大多数女人说得不够。
- I hate shy women.
- No one could ever call me shy...
- 我讨厌害羞的女人。
- 没有人说过我害羞…
Who'll come over to shoot
some lovely ducks?
谁会来这里射这些可爱的鸭子？
It will only cost you half a crown,
and it does such good for the orphans.
只花你半个钱币，为孤儿们做点好事。
Who'll come and shoot lovely ducks
here for half a crown?
谁过来花半个钱币射可爱的鸭子？
Only half a crown to shoot lovely ducks!
只要半个钱币可以射可爱的鸭子！
Eve.
Eve。
Excuse me.
不好意思。
Look, Eve, hold everything.
I have an idea.
你看，Eve，停下来。我有个主意。
Get Smith into Charlotte's tent,
as near the front as you can.
带Smith去Charlotte的帐幕，你尽量接近前面。
Go on, quickly.
继续，快点。
- What do you say we hear Charlotte sing?
- Oh, do let's.
- 我们听Charlotte唱歌好不好？
- 噢，我们去吧。
The murder makes her so interesting.
凶手让她很有兴趣。
- You know, I think I'll wait outside.
- But you promised.
- 你也知道，我想我在外边等。
- 但你答应过。
- I promised?
- In the taxi.
- 我答应过？
- 我计程车上。
You said the first thing we'd do would be
to go hear Charlotte Inwood.
你说第一件要做的事是去听Charlotte Inwood。
Don't you remember?
你还记得吗？
Do you know? I can't remember.
你知道吗？我不记得。
I must have had some sort of a blackout.
我一定是有点失去知觉。
- Oh, do let's hurry. We'll miss her.
- I think she's just dreamy.
- 噢，我们快点。我们要错过了。
- 我想她在睡觉。
Only half a crown to shoot a lovely duck!
只要半个钱币就可以射可爱的鸭子！
You can win a lovely prize!
Heavenly prizes!
你可以赢到可爱的奖品！丰富的奖品！
Only half a crown to shoot...
Would you like to shoot?
只要半个钱币就可以射…
你想射一下吗？
No, no. I hate firearms. I wonder
if I could buy one of those dolls.
不，不。我讨厌枪。我可否买个娃娃。
- A doll?
- Yes, please.
- 一个娃娃？
- 是，麻烦你。
- Which doll?
- Oh, any doll. That doll.
- 那一个？
- 噢，随便。就那一个。
- I suppose, but you'll have to pay for it.
- I know, but how much, please?
- 我想可以，但你要付钱买。
- 我知道，但多少钱，麻烦你？
- Well, it's for the orphans.
- Yes, I know, but how much?
- 那，这是为了孤儿的。
- 是，我知道，但多少钱？
- You are sorry for the orphans, aren't you?
- Of course I am, but how much?
- 你替孤儿们难过，是吗？
- 我当然会，但多少钱？
We all are, aren't we? Well, I suppose...
我们都是，对不对？那，我想…
...at least four pounds.
…最少四英镑。
- Give me the gun.
- Well, half a crown, then.
- 把枪给我。
- 那就，半个钱币。
- Yes.
- You know. Money first.
- 好。
- 你也明白。先给钱。
- Now, shall I put it in for you?
- Yes, please.
- 现在，我替你放进去好吗？
- 好，麻烦你。
It breaks somewhere here. I can't...
它在这附近断了。我不能…
It's rather...
这有点…
Perhaps I can manage.
或许我有办法。
Wait a minute. I think you'll have to do
it yourself. I'm not frightfully good.
等一下。我想你要自己搞定。我不是那么能干。
Be rather careful, won't you?
You know, it goes off.
请小心点，好吗？你知道吗，会走火。
Got you again, my beauty.
又打到你了，小可爱。
My bird, I think, sir.
我想，是我打的鸟，先生。
Could I have the doll, please?
我可以拿那娃娃吗，麻烦你？
What did you say?
你说什么？
Good shot, sir.
射得好，先生。
Well done. I'll get you your doll.
做得好。我去给你拿娃娃。
Here you are, sir. Now, then,
who's going to shoot lovely ducks?
这就是，先生。现在，谁要射可爱的鸭子？
Would you like to shoot lovely ducks?
你要射可爱的鸭子吗？
- Yes. Half a crown's worth.
- You sure that's enough?
- 对。半个钱币真值。
- 你肯定足够吗？
Oh, yes, certainly. Yes, I don't need
any more. I very seldom miss.
噢，是，当然够。
对，我不需要更多。我很少失手。
Oh, got it at last. Could I have
the doll, please?
噢，终于打到。我可以拿那娃娃吗，麻烦你？
I'm sorry, sir, but I'm afraid that's mine.
对不起，先生，我想那是我的。
What did you say?
你说什么？
Nothing at all.
没什么。
- Could I have the doll, please?
- Well done. I'll go and get it for you.
- 我可以拿那娃娃吗，麻烦你？
- 做得好。我去给你拿。
It is rather nice, I think,
to have won it, don't you?
我觉得能赢到这个，挺好的，是不是？
You did earn it that time. They're lovely
dolls. They're fully dressed. Fully.
你这次真的赚到了。他们真是可爱的娃娃。
还穿上整套衣服。整套。
Thank you very much.
多谢你。
Now, who's going to come and shoot lovely
duck over here for only half a crown?
现在，谁要到这里来
只花半个钱币就可以射可爱的鸭子？
We're having such fun over here shooting
duck for only half a crown!
这里非常有趣只花半个钱币就可以射鸭子！
Eve.
Eve。
I'm sorry.
对不起。
Ladies and gentlemen.
女士和先生们。
Doris. Doris!
Doris。Doris！
Miss Tinsdale!
Tinsdale小姐！
Come and give a hand here.
过来帮帮忙。
What are you waiting for?
你还在等什么？
I'm sorry, sir.
对不起，先生。
Do you think there's anything between
Cooper and Miss Inwood?
你觉得Cooper和Inwood小姐之间
有没有什么关系？
But Eve hasn't been near for days.
但Eve这几天都不在。
Doris! Miss Tinsdale!
Doris！Tinsdale小姐！
We got away as quickly as possible,
and here we are.
我们已经尽快离开，终于到了。
And that's the story of the short
and stormy life of Doris Tinsdale.
这就是Doris Tinsdale的短暂又多灾多难的人生。
It is in many respects a sad one,
but, one hopes...
在很多方面都是悲哀的，但，总希望…
...not entirely without usefulness.
…不是完全没用。
The next thing is to wait
for the arrival of Mr. Ordinary Smith...
接下来就是等普通Smith先生来。
...with his posse to arrest
the whole boiling lot of us.
…他的职责是把我们这帮人全逮捕。
Well, you think I should give myself up,
is that it?
那，你觉得我应该自首，是不是？
Yes, I should, shouldn't I? The longer
I stay here, the worse it will be for you.
是，我应该，不是吗？我在这越久，对你越麻烦。
But I won't give up. There must be
a way to get at Charlotte.
但我不会放弃。一定有办法逮到Charlotte的。
Now, I've made a nice hot toddy
for you, Mr. Robinson.
来了，我给你弄了一杯热toddy，Robinson先生。
There's nothing like it for a cold,
is there?
没有其他比这个对感冒好，是不是？
Thank you.
谢谢。
Isn't it dreadful? Mr. Robinson hasn't been
able to stir out of his room since he arrived.
是不是很绝望？从到这里起
Robinson先生都不能离开房间。
These spring colds are really frightful.
这些春天的感冒真是挺可怕。
Oh, by the way, Eve, Mr. Smith
is downstairs and wants to see you.
噢，Eve，Smith先生在楼下，他想见你。
I think it would be such a good idea...
我想会是个好主意…
...if I made Mr. Robinson a nice,
hot mustard plaster.
…如果我弄个热的介末意粉，给Robinson先生。
I wonder if he's got a temperature.
不知道他是否发烧。
I've broken my thermometer, but you could
easily run to the chemist's...
我打破了的探热针，但你很容易可以找到药店…
How long have you been
Miss Inwood's maid?
你当了Inwood的女佣有多久？
As I think you know, we've been anxious
to ask Doris Tinsdale a few questions.
我想你也知道，
我们急于要问Doris Tinsdale几个问题。
- I can explain...
- Did you talk to Jonathan Cooper last night?
- 我可以解析…
- 你昨晚有没有跟Jonathan Cooper说话？
- No.
- Did you see him?
- 没有。
- 你有没有见过他？
- Yes.
- Where?
- 有。
- 在哪？
On his way to Miss Inwood's dressing room.
在他去Inwood小姐更衣室途中。
He was there when she went up to change.
当她上去换衣服时他就在哪里。
I listened at the door and overheard
him say something about...
我在门外听到他说些关于…
...a bloodstained dress belonging to her.
…一条属于她染有血迹的裙子。
And then suddenly, she became afraid.
突然间，她变得很害怕。
Do you hear? Afraid.
你听见？害怕。
When you took Sergeant Loomis
up to the room...
当你带Loomis警长上去那房间…
...you presumed Cooper to be still there?
…你以为Cooper还在那里？
Well, I didn't know.
那，我不知道。
No, you didn't know,
but you had a pretty fair idea.
不，你不知道，但你相信是。
Why didn't you tell Loomis?
为什么你不告诉Loomis？
Then you did a very neat fainting fit, which
probably allowed Cooper to get clear away.
然后你刚好有点晕，
很可能就让Cooper有机会离开。
Don't talk like that.
不要这样说。
I can't bear it.
我受不了。
I don't understand it.
我不明白。
- How could you behave like that?
- But I can explain.
- 你怎可以用这态度？
- 但我解释不了。
I don't think that's necessary.
我不觉得有这需要。
In my job, I find a woman goes to almost
any length to protect her lover.
在工作中，我发现一个女人
为了保护她爱人不顾一切。
But it's not like that.
但不是这样。
It's not like that at all.
根本不是这样。
I thought I was in love with Jonathan...
我想我爱上Jonathan…
...but I'm not anymore.
…但现在没有了。
But it doesn't mean I won't go on
helping him, as I would any innocent man.
但这不代表我不会帮他，
就像对其他无辜的人一样。
It's not for you to decide whether he's
innocent or not. You leave that to the law.
他是不是无辜不是又你来决定。
你应该让法律来决定。
The point is, you put yourself
and your father...
问题是，你把你和你爸…
...in a very serious position
by this infernal amateur meddling.
…因为这极丑恶的事处于一个很严重的处境。
How I'm going to get you out of it,
I don't know.
我怎样摆脱这一切，我不知道。
But you do want to get us out?
但你也想我们可以解脱？
In spite of the fact you made such
a fool of me, you mean.
虽然事实上你是那么愚蠢，像你说的。
Your acting in the taxi
was extremely clever.
你在的士上的表演是非常聪明。
I wasn't acting in the taxi.
我在的士上不是在表演。
I fell in love with someone,
and all my plans went out the window.
我爱上某人，我什么计划都抛诸脑后。
When we were in the taxi together, I felt
as though I were on a great golden cloud.
当我们一切在的士上，我觉得虽然我是多么伟大。
I told Father I didn't want to go on
with this. I wanted to tell you everything.
我告诉爸爸我不想继续下去。我想把一切告诉你。
But he had an idea about
a bloodstained doll, and I had to put it off.
但他有个染血娃娃的主意，所以我搁置了。
I wanted to tell you all about it.
我想告诉你所以事情。
Please believe me.
请相信我。
Would you like to mix a cocktail
yourself, Mr. Smith?
你想自己来调杯鸡尾酒吗，Smith先生？
I'm afraid there's no ice,
but I'm sure you can manage.
恐怕这里没有冰块，但我知道你能应付。
- Good evening, Smith.
- Good evening.
- 晚上好，Smith。
- 晚上好。
- Do I hear the muted clanking of chains?
- It's only the plumbing.
- 我好像听到有铁链撞击的声音？
- 只是那水泵。
It's in a dreadful state.
是很悲哀的状态。
How did you enjoy the garden party,
Mr. Smith?
园游会好玩吗，Smith先生？
It must have been awful in that rain.
在下雨一定很扫兴。
I think I'll take some sherry
up to Mr. Robinson.
我想拿点sherry酒上去给Robinson先生。
I've quite changed my mind about him.
He seems such a nice young man after all.
我对他的感觉改变不少。
说到底他好像是个不错的小伙子。
Eve, dear, you will look after
Mr. Smith, won't you?
Eve，亲爱的，你来招呼Smith先生，好吗？
Father, I've been explaining to Mr. Smith
what we're trying to do.
爸爸，我在跟Smith先生解释我们在做什么。
He thinks we ought to stop.
他觉得我们该停止。
Oh, what a pity.
噢，太可惜了。
Just when you and I were about to save
Mr. Smith so much trouble.
就在我和你快要省去Smith先生很多麻烦的时候。
Save me trouble?
省去我的麻烦？
Sir, you don't look like an irresponsible
imbecile. Why behave like one?
先生，你不像是个不负责任的傻瓜。
为什么这样做?
You let your daughter get mixed up in this?
What sort of father do you think you are?
你让你女儿牵涉这事？你想你是个怎样的父亲？
Unique. Quite unique.
特别。听特别的。
But rather broken-hearted at this moment.
You see, I have another idea.
但现在挺伤心的。你知道吗，我另外有个点子。
A pity to waste ideas, isn't it?
浪费点子是很可惜，不是吗？
Have you...? Have you ever
been blackmailed, Mr. Smith?
你有没有…？你有没有被勒索，Smith先生？
Well, I have. Only this afternoon.
唔，我有。就在这个下午。
At least my daughter and I were,
by Nellie Goode.
起码我女儿和我就有，被Nellie Goode。
Yes, most inappropriate name.
I told her so.
对，很不恰当的名字。我告诉过她。
She touched us for 24 pounds, and do you
know why I think it was well-spent?
她要我们24英镑，你知道为什么我觉得值得？
- Though we could ill afford it.
- Come to the point, please.
- 虽然我们是花不起。
- 快入正题，麻烦你。
Well, it struck me that what Nellie could do,
Doris could do.
那，让我很惊讶Nellie能做出，Doris那做出。
I mean suppose she went
to Miss Inwood and said:
我的意思是假如她去跟Inwood小姐说：
"Look, Miss Inwood,
I've got a certain dress of yours.
“你看，Inwood小姐，我有你某一条裙子。
It's ruined, but it's still worth money."
她怀了，但它依然很值钱。”
And suppose Miss Inwood said, "All right,
I'll give you 100 pounds for it."
假如Inwood小姐说，“好吧，我给你100英镑要它”
What then, eh?
那怎样，嗯？
And suppose you happened
to be listening.
假如你刚好听见。
Well, that's what police do
in blackmail cases, isn't it?
那，这是警察要管的勒索案，不是吗？
What about it, eh? What about it?
怎样，嗯？怎样？
Oh, you needn't be afraid that Doris
couldn't do it. She could do it, Doris could.
噢，你不用担心Doris做不来。
她办得到，Dois可以。
I mean, Eve could. She's a very good
actress, a very good actress indeed.
我意思是，Eve可以。她是个很好的演员，
一个确实是很好的演员。
I'm sure she is.
我肯定她是。
By the way,
is there a bloodstained dress?
说回来，是否有一条有血迹的裙子？
Well, no. No, not exactly.
那，没有。没有，不算有。
Look, there was
a bloodstained dress, only...
这，本来是有一条有血迹的裙子，只是。
- Couldn't we tell you...?
- I'm getting back to the office.
- 我们可否告诉你…？
- 我要会办公室。
I'll let you know about this later.
我晚一些再告诉你。
In the meantime, what's Miss Inwood
doing without a dresser?
同时，Inwood小姐没有服装师会怎样？
You better run along to the theater before
she starts getting impatient.
你最好在她没有耐性前回到剧院。
It's all right.
那好吧。
- What do you mean, "It's all right"?
- He's trying to save face.
- “那好吧”是什么意思？
- 他在挽回面子。
Not a bad face, either.
同时，也不想难看。
He'll let us do it. What's the matter
with you? Aren't you pleased?
他会让我们去做。你怎么啦？不高兴吗？
Come on. We better hurry.
来吧。我们快点。
Come to Burton Street and bring two men.
Post them at either end of the street.
去Burton街带两个人来。让他们守在街的两头。
I'll be waiting at the telephone booth
at the corner. All right?
我就在转角的电话亭里等着。没问题？
Hello. Is that Mrs. Gill?
Is the commodore available?
你好。是Gill小姐吗？指挥官在吗？
Oh, he's gone out. Is Miss Eve there?
噢，他出去了。Eve小姐在吗？
Oh, she's out too. No, one moment.
噢，她也出去了。不，等一下。
May I speak to Mr. Robinson, please?
我可以跟Robinson先生说话吗，麻烦你？
- What's your idea, governor?
- Just a little experiment.
- 你意思怎样，首长？
- 只是个小小实验。
- Plug it in.
- Okay.
- 去吧。
- 好。
The mike's in position.
米高峰已经到位。
I'm speaking about three foot from it.
Can you hear me?
我离它三英尺左右。
你听到我吗？
- Tell him the sound's all right.
- Okay.
- 告诉他声音没问题。
- 好。
Do you think it'll work?
你认为行得通吗？
What a day, darling.
难熬的一天，亲爱的。
I've never in my whole life been so glad
to see the end of it.
终于完了这辈子都没试过那么开心。
- Yes, madam.
- You must be tired too.
- 是，夫人。
- 是一定也很累。
It can't be easy to be a dresser
with no experience.
作为一个没经验的服装师也不容易。
But you're quite good.
Very good, indeed.
但你不错。确实不错。
Oh, that rain.
That rain at the garden party.
噢，那场雨。在园游会那场雨。
Thank goodness it didn't rain at the funeral.
That would have been too much.
还好在葬礼时没有下雨。
那就太多了。
I hate rainy funerals.
我讨厌葬礼上下雨。
And then somebody sent up
that disgusting doll.
还有某人送你那恶心的娃娃。
What vermin some vermin are.
害虫就是害虫。
Yes, madam.
是，夫人。
By the way, did the police find you?
话说回来，警察有没有找你？
I haven't seen them yet, madam.
我还没有看见他们，夫人。
And anyway,
I've got nothing to tell them.
不管怎样，我没什么要告诉他们。
Well, I suppose that's all.
那，我想也没什么了。
And that horrible Nellie
will be back tomorrow.
那可恶的Nellie明天就回来。
We may never see each other again.
Ships that pass in the something or other.
我们以后也不会见面了。天下无不散的宴席。
I like you. You're so very sweet and patient.
I don't suppose I'm easy to get on with.
我喜欢你。你很可爱又有耐性。
我不是那么容易相处的。
Oh, but you are, madam.
It's been wonderful working with you.
噢，但你是，夫人。为你工作非常好。
And I do love the theater so.
而且我也很喜欢剧院。
I don't see why. It's an awful life, really.
我不那么认为。这是讨厌的生活，真的。
Here, darling.
A little something extra for you.
这里，打令。还有些小东西给你。
I couldn't, madam. Honestly.
我不能要，夫人。真的。
Don't be an idiot. Put it in the bank
or go out and get drunk or something.
不要那么笨。放在银行或是去外边吃喝玩玩。
- Thank you, madam.
- Can I give you a lift?
- 谢谢你，夫人。
- 我可以送你一程吗？
- Lf you would drop me, I'd appreciate it.
- All right. Come along, then.
- 如果你载我一程，我会很感谢。
- 好吧。那么，一起走。
- Good night.
- 晚安。
- Miss Inwood, could I talk to you in private?
- We can talk in the car. That's private.
- Inwood小姐，我可以私底下跟你聊聊吗？
- 我们可以在车里谈。那是私人空间。
No, that won't do.
I've got to talk to you now.
不，那不行。我现在就要跟你说。
What's all this about?
这是关于什么？
Let's go someplace
where nobody can hear us.
我们去没有人听见的地方吧。
Good night.
晚安。
- Have you gone mad or something?
- No, madam.
- 你有毛病还是疯了？
- 不，夫人。
I want to tell you about
the bloodstained doll.
我想告诉你关于那有血迹的娃娃。
Well, what about that doll?
那娃娃有什么事？
Oh, I hate all this, madam.
I'm that nervous.
噢，我讨厌这一切，夫人。我非常紧张。
I'm so afraid of doing the wrong thing.
我好害怕坏了事。
You see, I have a dress that belongs to you
with a big bloodstain down the front.
你明白吗，我有一条属于你的裙子前面染了血迹。
By rights, I know I should
go to the police...
正常来说，我知道我应该去找警察…
...but, to tell you the truth,
madam, I'm afraid.
…但，老实告诉你，夫人，我害怕。
My dad would murder me
if I got my name in the papers.
我爸会把我杀了如果我的名字上报。
So, you see, I've come to you.
Maybe you could tell me what to do.
所以，你也明白，我来找你。
或许你可以告诉我应该怎样做。
How much do you want?
你想要多少？
Money never entered my head, madam.
I hope you won't think that of me.
我没想过要钱，夫人。
我希望你不要这样想我。
Only if the dress were clean like new,
it might be worth, say, 75 or 100 pounds.
我只想如果那裙子像新的一样干净，
它可能值，大概，75到100英镑。
I know nothing about
a bloodstained dress.
对有血迹的裙子我就一无所知了。
This sounds to me remarkably
like blackmail.
我听起来好像是勒索。
- I think I'd better call the police.
- Yes. Do call the police, Miss Inwood.
- 我想我还是报警比较好。
- 对。应该报警，Inwood小姐。
We'll talk to them together.
我们一起去吧。
- You're not the maid.
- No, I'm not.
- 你不是个佣人。
- 不，我不是。
Why have you been pretending
all this time?
为什么你一直装着？
Shall we say we needed evidence?
可以说我们需要证据吗？
We? Are you from the police?
我们？你是警察派来的吗？
How was the bloodstain
smeared on the dress?
那血迹怎样沾到裙子上？
Who are you?
你是谁？
Why were you so frightened when Jonathan
said he hadn't destroyed the dress?
当Jonathan说他没有毁灭那裙子
你为什么会那么害怕？
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- You do know!
- 我不知道你在说什么。
- 你是知道的！
Yes.
是。
Some blood did splash on my dress.
有些血是喷到我的裙子上。
I was there when Jonathan
killed my husband.
当Jonathan杀我丈夫时我是在场。
- That's not true.
- It is, but I had nothing to do with it.
- 那不是事实。
- 是事实，但我跟这事无关。
Jonathan wanted my name kept out of it.
Jonathan想我置身事外。
He sent me back to his rooms.
我送我回到他的房间。
He stayed behind to make it look
like robbery.
他留下来弄成好像是打劫。
- Then he brought me a clean dress.
- You're lying.
- 然后他带我一条干净的裙子。
- 你说谎。
It's a sacred truth. I swear to you it is.
千真万确。我可以向你发誓。
Listen, whoever you are...
听着，不管你是谁…
...I'll give you anything
if you keep me out of this.
…我什么都可以给你
如果你让我置身事外。什么都可以。
My jewelry is worth over 10,000 pounds.
You can have it all.
我的珠宝价值超过一万英镑。
可以全部给你。
And my furs or money.
How much do you want?
还有我的皮草和钱。
你想要多少？
I'll give you anything. Anything.
我所以都给你。所有。
I'm going now to break it up.
Bring them in. I want them together.
我现在就去破案。带她们进来。我要她们一起。
You deliberately tried to pin
it all on Jonathan...
你故意把一切推到
Jonathan身上…
...assisted by Mr. Freddie Williams.
- It's not true, I tell you. It's not!
…由Freddie Williams先生协助。
- 这不是事实，我告诉你，这不是！
Well, you won't get away with it.
I warn you, that's all.
唔，你是脱不了罪的。
我警告你，就这样。
I've had a terrible scene
with a lunatic girl.
我刚跟一个疯女孩有可怕的一幕。
First she pretended to be my dresser,
then a detective and tried to blackmail me.
首先她扮成我的服装师，然后是侦探和想勒索我。
That's all right, Miss Inwood. You stay here.
I'll have a word with you in a minute.
没问题，Inwood小姐。你留在这里。
我等一下会再跟你说。
Oh, good. They got him.
噢，好。他们抓到他。
Jonathan, what have they done to you?
Jonathan，他们把你怎样了？
Why are you arresting him?
你为什么要逮捕他？
Mellish, stand by Miss Inwood there!
Mellish，站在Inwood小姐旁边！
Heavens, that must be Cooper.
天呀，一定是Cooper。
Where's Miss Inwood?
Inwood小姐在哪里？
Cover the alleyway in case he used
an emergency door.
守住小巷子以防他用太平门。
- Where do those stairs lead to?
- Dressing rooms.
- 那些楼梯通到哪里？
- 更衣室。
Eve! Eve, come back!
Eve！Eve，回来！
Where's the nearest telephone?
最近的电话在哪里？
- Eve.
- He came through an emergency door.
- Eve。
- 他穿过了太平门。
Hurry up downstairs. Go on, hurry!
快下楼梯。来吧，快点！
Get back into the theater.
回到剧院里去。
Have you been told
to keep an eye on me?
有没有人叫你看着我？
In a manner of speaking, yes.
口头上来说，有。
- In that case, may I sit down?
- No harm in that.
- 这样的话，我可以坐下吗？
- 这没什么。
Get me a chair, then.
那么，拿张椅子给我。
Surely, ma'am. Surely.
当然可以，夫人。当然。
- Done with the mike?
- Yes.
- 米高峰用完了？
- 是。
Okay. I wonder if they caught...
好。不知道他们有没有抓到…
What's the point of going up to the roof?
这是通往屋顶的吗？
He may have doubled back along the alley
and gone up the fire escape.
他可能从小巷跑回并爬上火警楼梯。
- So they've heard everything I said?
- Yes.
- 所以他们听到我所说的一切？
- 是。
- And it's all in that book?
- All in there, in shorthand.
- 所有都在那本子上？
- 所有都在那，用速记。
How clever of you.
你真聪明。
Things look bad for me, don't they?
情况对我不利，是不是？
I'm what you'd call an accessory...
I suppose.
我就是你说的一件配件…
我认为是。
- George!
- Yes?
- George！
- 是？
Smith wants you down
at the stage doorkeeper's office.
Smith想你下去舞台的门卫室。
Thank you, darling.
谢谢你，打令。
We'll need more men to cover
all the rooms in this place...
我们需要更多人手去把守这里的每间房…
It's not all in there.
不是都在那里。
- What's your name?
- Mellish.
- 你叫什么名字？
- Mellish。
- Do you like dogs, Mellish?
- Yes, ma'am, I do.
- 你喜欢狗吗，Mellish？
- 对，夫人，为喜欢。
But not all dogs.
但不是所有狗。
If they don't love you,
you don't love them.
如果他们不喜欢你，你也不喜欢他们。
- That's right, isn't it?
- I suppose so.
- 对，不是吗？
- 我认为是。
I had a dog once. He hated me.
我曾经有过一支狗。他讨厌我。
At last he bit me, and I had him shot.
最后他咬我，我把他射杀了。
When I give all my love and get back
treachery and hatred, it's...
当我把所有爱付出而得到背叛和憎恨，就…
It's as if my mother
had struck me in the face.
就好像我母亲打我的脸一样。
Do you understand that, Mellish?
你明白这些吗，Mellish？
I've heard it takes them
that way sometimes.
我听过有时会是这样。
Yes. It takes some of them that way.
是。有些会是这样。
- Has Miss Inwood gone yet?
- No, she's in the theater.
- Inwood小姐走了没有？
- 没有，她在剧院里。
- Don't you think he's well away now?
- I'm sure I saw him run down the alley.
- 你不记得他已经跑得老远吗？
- 我肯定看见他走下小巷。
This is Smith.
这是Smith。
We're covering the theater
from the roof to the storeroom.
我们把剧院从屋顶到储物室都守住。
- Fine, sir.
- You heard what Miss Inwood said.
- 好，先生。
- 你听到Inwood小姐说什么了。
You can't have anything
against Cooper now.
你现在没有什么可以控告Cooper了。
Nothing, except murder. He killed
Charlotte's husband, all right.
没有，除了谋杀。他杀了Charlotte的丈夫，对吧。
He's killed before.
他之前已经被杀。
What? What do you mean?
什么？你是什么意思？
He got away with it last time with a plea
of self-defense. He won't this time.
他上次脱罪是因为自卫。这次他不可以了。
- But Eve.
- She's alone with him now.
- 但Eve。
- 她现在跟他独处。
Can't you see, sir?
She's in very great danger.
你不明白吗，先生？
她现在非常危险。
It all adds up to a confession,
except she said you killed him.
这些加起来只是种忏悔，除了她说你杀了他。
Anyone in their right mind
could see she was telling a lie.
任何正常人都看得出她在说谎。
But I don't understand why Smith
arrested you. What happened?
但我不明白为什么Smith逮捕你。发生什么事？
Somebody phoned and said
the police were on their way.
有人打来说警察快到。
I made a bolt for it, and they
grabbed me at the street door.
我马上走出去，但他们就在门外把我逮着。
Funny, that.
Getting me out into the street.
有趣，那电话。让我走到街上去。
I suppose Smith didn't want me
to be caught in your house.
我认为Smith不想我在屋里被抓。
That would have been awkward for you,
wouldn't it?
那会让你难堪，不是吗？
I don't think they'll look
for us here for a bit.
我想他们不会来在这里找我们。
After a while, maybe we can make
a dash through an emergency exit.
过一会，或许我们可以从紧急出口冲出去。
Eve. Eve. Eve, wherever you are,
come away from him.
Eve。Eve。Eve，不管你在哪，远离他。
Come away from him.
He's dangerous. He's a killer.
远离他。他是危险人物。他是杀人犯。
Eve? Eve?
Eve？Eve？
You're right, you know.
Charlotte was telling the truth.
你是对的，你也知道。Charlotte是说真话。
What she didn't tell you was that
she goaded me into doing it.
她没有告诉你的是她诱迫这样做。
She set me against him
in every way she could.
她用尽方法让我跟他对抗。
She made me think she was crazy
about me, but she wasn't.
她让我觉得她迷恋我，但她不是。
I was to kill her husband to leave
the coast clear for that Freddie Williams.
我去杀他丈夫使她可以跟Freddie Williams一起。
I know that now.
She knew the sort of man I was.
我现在知道了。她了解我是那一类男人。
She knows I can't control myself
if I get into a rage.
她知道如果我愤怒我是不能控制自己。
Like a fool, I told her
about that girl I'd killed.
像个傻瓜，我告诉她关于我杀的那个女孩。
Oh, Jonathan. Jonathan,
you don't know what you're saying.
噢，Jonathan。Jonathan，你不知道你在说什么。
I can't help it, Eve. I can't control
myself, even when I was a kid.
我没办法，Eve。当我还是小孩的时候，
我也控制不了自己。
I was lucky that last time. The little
fool threatened me with a gun.
上一次是我运气好。那小笨蛋用枪来吓唬我。
But you don't know what it's like
to have a thing like this hanging over you.
但你不知道当这样的事发生在你身上会是怎样。
Eve, I hated to tell you that
phony story in your car that time...
Eve，我不想告诉你那次在你车上的无稽故事…
...but there was no other way.
…但是别无他法。
Charlotte did go on to my flat
after I'd killed her husband.
我杀了他丈夫后Charlotte是来过我家。
Her dress was stained a bit,
so I brought her a clean one.
她的裙子是沾污了一点，
所以我带了一条干净的给她。
Then when she went to the theater...
当她去了剧院…
...I made a big stain on it
to make you believe me.
…我染了一大片血迹在上面使你相信我。
I'm telling you the truth now.
我现在跟你说实话。
Jonathan...
Jonathan…
...I feel desperately sorry for you.
…我对你感到极之难过。
Really, I do.
真的，我是。
No, you don't. You're not sorry at all.
不，你不是。你一点都没有感到难过。
You don't care what happens to me.
你不关心我会发生什么事。
Jonathan...
Jonathan…
...you could give yourself up.
They'd take care of you.
…你可以去自首。他们会照顾你。
You couldn't do all these things
unless you...
你不会做出这一切除非你…
Unless...
除非…
They can't do anything to a sick man,
and that's what you are. You must be.
他们可以用尽方法去让某人发病，
你就是这样。你一定是。
No. They're going to hang me.
They'll hang Charlotte, too, for planning it.
不。他们会把我吊死。
他们会同时吊死Charlotte，因为是她策划。
They've never forgiven me for getting
away with it the first time.
他们从没放过我因为我逃过第一次。
There's nothing wrong with my mind.
Nobody can prove that there is, unless...
我的精神没问题。没有人能证明我有，除非…
Unless I do it a third time...
除非我做出第三次…
...with no reason whatever.
…毫无原因的。
That would be a clear case of insanity.
那将会是明显的神经错乱。
Wouldn't it?
不是吗？
Jonathan. Jonathan,
I don't hear a sound now.
Jonathan。Jonathan，我现在什么都听不到。
I think we can go now.
我想我们现在可以走了。
We'll go out through the orchestra pit,
and then I'll take you to my father's boat.
我们在乐队包厢穿过，然后我去取我爸爸的船。
Come along.
跟着我。
Here he is!
他在这！
Look! In the orchestra pit!
看！在乐队包厢！
Mathews, quick! Down in the orchestra!
Mathews，快！在下面乐队席！
- They've got him!
- Where?
- 他们抓到他了！
- 在哪？
- They found him.
- Where was he?
- 他们找到他。
- 他在哪？
- He was in the theater after all.
- Call Smith!
- 我一直在剧院。
- 打给Smith！
- He was at the stage doorkeeper's office.
- Drop the iron curtain, cut him off!
- 他在舞台的门卫室。
- 放下铁幕，挡住他！
Get out! Move your head
out of the way!
出来！把你的头移开！
- Take the curtain up.
- Don't touch anything.
- 升起铁幕。
- 不要碰任何东西。
Mellish, you'd better phone
up the photographer.
Mellish，你最好去打电话给摄影师。
Someone find out if Byard's here yet.
Tell him what's happened.
有没有人看见Byard来了没有。
告诉他发生什么事。